<topics>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-billy-sunday</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-07-06/ed-1/?sp=22&amp;q=billy+sunday&amp;r=0.279,0.45,0.947,0.471,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Billy Sunday who used to play right
                        field with Captain Ansons White Stock
                        ings counted up the other day and
                        found that his soul saving operations
                        throughout the Middle West during the
                        past year had netted him somewhere In
                        the neighborhood of 12000 says the
                        Brooklyn Eagle Mr Sunday is not
                        merctnary and he thinks more of con
                        verts than he does of mency but he
                        mentioned his profits to en Interviewer
                        simply because he had been asked If it
                        hadnt been something in the nature of
                        a sacrifice to shift from tho high salary
                        of a professional baseball player to the
                        supposed uncertain Income of an itin
                        erant evangelist
                        GoJ has been right good to us Is
                        the way Mr Sunday puts It He gave
                        us 100 for a months work In
                        dcre 111 J1200 for the same length of
                        time In Farpilngton and even In frosty
                        Whcaton where they are mostly Chi
                        cago millionaires we drew S0O la
                        thirty days
                        Since success even of an evangelical
                        sort Is mensured in a way by the amount
                        of ones income the ball player revival
                        ist and his friends figure that ho Is the
                        ton notcher among evangelists Cer
                        tainly no one since Mr Moodys death
                        has saved so many of the perishing or
                        made so much money while doing It
                        Out In Iowa where Mr Sunday has con
                        verted more than 10000 persons during
                        his ministry people assert that he Is
                        destined to be a greater revivalist than
                        Mr Moody He has enough calls now
                        from Western towns which think they
                        need chastening to occupy all of his
                        time for the next eighteen months
                        These things have a tendency to make
                        Mr Sunday rather more than satisfied
                        with the fate that tempted him away
                        from the diamond and a 3000 salary
                        about ten years ago He thinks the
                        luckiest thing that ever happened him
                        was when an Iowa rustic he wandered
                        into a mission In Chicago and was per
                        suaded by the words of a revivalist and
                        the music of a wheezy reed organ to
                        be born again On that night twenty
                        years ago Mr Sunday decided he would
                        become a preacher The Idea stuck in
                        his brain through all his brilliant career
                        as a ball player until he found the op
                        portunity to abandon professional ath
                        letlcs and enter the Young Mens Chris
                        tian Association as an assistant secre
                        tary at S00 a year He had educated
                        himself at Northwestern University
                        while he was playing ball so he was
                        fairly well equipped to take up the
                        work of exhortation and advice
                        Mr Sundays revival methods are all
                        his own He throws out the life line
                        In a fashion distinctly unique No
                        shouting and Jumping no frenzy and no
                        hysterics among the converts at his
                        meetings He talks to his congregations
                        in a sane and reasonable fashion When
                        ho has them convinced that they are a
                        pretty bad lot he asks them to come
                        to the front There are no mourners
                        benches Instead thercarc chairs upon
                        which he invites the penitents to sit
                        while he circulates among them and
                        talks to them calmly He takes the
                        name of each subject and turns him over
                        to the pastor of the denomination for
                        which he expresses a preference and
                        refuses to be longer responsible for him
                        Mr Sunday himself Is affiliated with no
                        denomination 4
                        His plan Is to stay a month in each
                        place For the first two weeks he does
                        not give the Invitation He tells the
                        people funny stories and amuies them
                        with certain bizarre methods of preach
                        ing The third week he devotes to- an
                        exposition of sin as he has found it
                        among the people with whom he is
                        laboring During the fourth week he
                        shows the sinner tho way to repentance
                        He Is a lithe well built swarthy
                        chap forty years old and with the look
                        of n man much younger In the pulpit
                        ho wears business clothing well tailored
                        and with some pretension to prcalllng
                        styles If he gets warm ho removes his
                        coat not because he Is warm neces
                        sarily but because it makes him differ
                        ent from other preachers That is his
                        principal aim to be illflcreut In
                        Wheaton the other night he made a run
                        ning leap from the pulpit landed in the
                        aisle and sprinted areund the church
                        preachlns all the while
                        This Is a frosty town he shouted
                        but I am determined by the grace of
                        God to change It
                        He did change It to some extent
                        Wheaton Is an aristocratic suburb the
                        scat of the Chicago Golf Club and the
                        summer home of many well known Chi
                        cagoans It Is not the most promising
                        field therefore for evangelical opera
                        tions But Mr Sunday thought the peo
                        ple needed a moral Jolting and he made
                        arrangements to preach to them for a
                        month The first week the revival there
                        -was rather a frost Wheaton didnt
                        care much for funny stories and it uad
                        little curiosity to hear the preaching of
                        an ex baseball player So Mr Sunday
                        was forced to look into his resources
                        He loafed around the drug store and tho
                        postoffice for a few mornings until he
                        got a line on the moral condition of the
                        place Then he permitted some of hU
                        Information to percolate through his
                        sermons The consequence was that In
                        a night or two Wheaton began to notice
                        him
                        Next he attacked Sunday golf In such
                        -vigorous fashion that the capitalists
                        who use the links of the Chicago Club
                        iound themselves without caddleson the
                        Sabbath day Card playing and dancing
                        too fell under the ban of his eloquence
                        You cant waltz to heaven he said
                        and neither can you two step after you
                        get there The lowest down rascal in
                        any community is a dancing Methodist
                        Jle does it for the Bug not for the
                        dance Dancing Is a secondary Iove
                        fleast set to music The gambling spirit
                        is engendered in American children by
                        their euchre playing mothers I have
                        Just as much respect for a gambler who
                        will sit in a Joint and buck a Jack pot
                        until 3 oclock In the morning as I have
                        for a woman who will parade under tho
                        garb of respectability at euchre or cinch
                        parties
                        This was peculiar preaching for
                        Wheaton but Cary Memorial Church
                        was full every night and 205 persons
                        mostly men were converted In on
                        month
                        One night he ordered a group of Fre
                        Mfcthodlsts to leave the church and on
                        a lother occasion he suggested that the
                        Instructress of the towns smartest
                        dzaiclng class make her exit which she
                        did He Jumped over the pulpit on
                        evening to Illustrate the methods of aa
                        old time Methodist Episcopal shouter
                        Mr Sunday never fails to take ad
                        vantage of an opportunity to play ball
                        and be often Is the star feature of the
                        loial games wherever he happens to b
                        priachlng His gestures and occasion
                        ally his language savor of the game
                        although when he cares to he can preaca
                        as dignified a sermon as one would car
                        to tear
                        Mr Sunday was born In Iowa and -was
                        takjen from an orphans home by Lieu
                        tenant Governor Scott who reared him
                        His father was killed In the civil war
                        He -went to Chicago in 18S3 as a profet
                        slotial baseball player and was under
                        Ansun for fire years Subsequently h
                        playnd on the National League teams
                        of Pittsburg and Philadelphia
                        Ho has never been quite weaned from
                        the professional game His home in
                        Chicago Is within a few squares of the
                        National League park and he Is always
                        a spectator at the games when his
                        preaching engagements will permit</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1904-08-29/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=billy+suday&amp;r=-0.703,0.064,2.406,1.197,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1903-05-13/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=billy+sunday&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.136,-0.066,0.833,0.829,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Heres the story Billy Bill Sunday Sunda tells of ofthe ofthe ofthe
                        he way wa lie came to change his mind mindabout mindt mtndabout
                         about ball playing and take to the min mini minIBtrr mm mmIstry
                         latry Sunday Sunda was recently ordained an anevangelist anevangelist anevangelist
                        vangelist and is now known as the theRev theRci theIVilliam
                        ev William A Sunday SundayFifteen SundayFlfteen
                         Fifteen rt e years ago one Sunday night I Iwalkeddown Iwalked Iwalkeddown
                        alked walkeddown down State Street Chicago ChicagoJn ChicagoJncomiany in incompany incompany
                        ompany company with several ball players playerswhose playerswhose playerswhose
                        hose names were worldrenowned and andsome andsome andsome
                        ome of o whom are now dead We TO en entered entered entered
                        ered a saloon drank and passed on to tothe tothe tothe
                        he corner of State and Van Buren Burenwhere Burenwhere Burenwhere
                        here Siegel Coopers store now nowstands noWstands nowstands
                        tands There was a company of men menand menand menand
                        nd women singing We sat on the thecurbstone thes thecurbstone
                         curbstone and listened I had heard heardthose1 heardII heardthosedongs
                        I those1 thosedongs songs from mother back In Iowa Iowaand
                         and an fnrthe the Methodist Sunday Sunda school in inflj InP Inand
                        lj jngsjpJEQwa P R aand and God palnted paIntedon on n the thecanvas thecanyaso thecanyas
                        anvas canyaso of o my memory memor the scenes and andrecollections andr andrecollections
                        ecollections r of other days da s and faces facesI
                         I bowed my m head in shame and the thetears thetears theV
                         tears rolled down my cheeks ch eks like rlv rlvers nvc lv lvers
                         ers of water When hen the song was end ended ended ended
                        d Where Is My Iy Wandering Boy To Tonight Tonight Tonight
                        ight l the leader who proved to be beHarry beHarry beV
                         Harry Monroe of the Pacific Garden GardenMission GardenMission GardenV
                         Mission said Come boys down to tothe tothe tothe
                        he mission and listen to the speaking speakingand
                        nd singing I arose and said Boys Boysgoodby Boysgoodb
                         goodby Im done with this way Wa of lIv HvIng lIving livV
                         Ing and went to the mission missionwent missionwentCyery missionwentevery went wentevery
                        very night for two weeks Ono night nightMrs nightMrs nightMrs
                        rs Colonel Clark Invited me forward forwardto
                         to the altar I went and professed faith faithin faithin faithin
                        n Christ</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1909-02-12/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=Billy+Sunday&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.342,0.576,1.459,0.726,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Billy Sunday, the man who has b.een
                        fighting the devil since he ceased chas
                        ing flies and liners over the green dia
                        monds of the National league, graced
                        San Francisco" with his presence yes
                        torday afternoon for the first time.
                        Before bedtime fully 10,000 knew that
                        the king of the evangelists was among
                        them. Half that number heard him in
                        his tirade against sin at Dreamland
                        rink, and the other half had wind of

                        the sensation which lie started in the
                        City of Sensations. He swooped down
                        upon the multitude like a Kansas
                        He flayed all classes alike,
                        rich and poor and high and low. He
                        grave his listeners a shaking up such as
                        they have not experienced since April
                        There are evangelists and evangelists,
                        'and preachers and missionaries, but
                        there is only one Billy Sunday. We
                        \u25a0 have heard much of his prowess and
                        his peculiarities and his spellbinding
                        methods, but none of these do the man
                        justice. He is in a class which none
                        of the others have as yet invaded. He
                        has his own style and his own tactics,
                        and nobody can appreciate what it all
                        Is till he or she has heard the former
                        ball player and seen him act.
                        /WAGES SPECIAL WAR
                        He wages war on Beelzebub with his
                        own special process a process which
                        nobody else has thus far mastered. He
                        goes "at his work rough shod*and he
                        is brimfull of that kind of enthusiasm
                        which wins men. women and children to
                        his way of thinking. He talks to them
                        Sn the jargon of the diamond and the
                        slang of the street, and he comes back
                        again at them with biblical quotations
                        arid passages from the works of the
                        old masters and the Grecian authors.
                        He has everything that a man needs to
                        mystify and awe and convert an audi
                        ence. There is nothing lacking in his
                        wonderful makeup. When he starts he
                        2:as everybody with him.
                        There never was an evangelist nor a
                        public speaker who boasted a more un
                        usual career than this same Billy Sun
                        day. 'Tis hard to believe that this man
                        who is now fighting the fight of the
                        Lorof the good old palmy days of the dia
                        mond, who used to think more of a
                        two base hit than he did of the king
                        •dom of heaven. It is hard to combine
                        two more difficult callings than the one
                        which Sunday followed .25 years ago
                        and the one which is his today.
                        WHITE SOX HERO
                        A quarter of a century back Sunday
                        was the right fielder on the famous old
                        Chicago White Sox team, one of the
                        most historic that Uncle Sam's great
                        national pastime ever knew. Then he
                        was the diamond hero of the hour,
                        sharing the honors with the mighty
                        John Clarkson, Mike Kelly, Pop Anson,
                        Ed Williamson, George Gore and the
                        others, whose memories will never die
                        so long as the game of baseball lives
                        and prospers.
                        Sunday was the fleetest runner of the
                        diamond in those days, and, incidental
                        ly, the man has never played ball since
                        who could travel over the paths ag the
                        now renowned evangelist used to. He
                        •was the pride of Chicago and the pet
                        oT Anson, the man who led the fighting
                        ball team to so many glorious victories.
                        .Xobody, not even Sunday himself, ever
                        breamed that a few more years would
                        find him. on the road preaching relig
                        ion Instead of- laying down bunts to
                        \u25a0win games for Chicago.
                        But Sunday got religion one mem
                        orable day and the seemingly Improb
                        able came to pass. He responded to the
                        call and In the tumult of his environ
                        ment he 'orgot the ball field, where he
                        bad labored and fought for so many
                        fears. He was laughed at and ridi
                        culed and, scorned by fans and players
                        alike, but nothing could stay his deter
                        mination to take up the burden in the
                        name of his Creator. He entered upon
                        his new career full of confidence and
                        zeal and he has been fighting a winning
                        figilt ever since.
                        BIBLE REPLACES BAT.
                        "Once I dreamed of nothing but
                        knocking the ball out of the lot," said
                        Sunday yesterday, "but now my ambi
                        tion is to knock the devil out of the
                        hearts of sinners. The bible has taken
                        the place of the bat in my affections,
                        ..and 1 hope to score as many sinners
                        as I did bases in those good old days
                        when the White Soy used to beat them
                        all and we barred no team."
                        Engrossed as he is in his new life,
                        Billy Sunday still loves the game of
                        baseball. He. can't forget.lt. Even in
                        his sermons he must refer to it. The
                        ?port took a deep root in his. heart.
                        when he was but a lad and he uses it
                        now in his crusade against £in. Base
                        ball to him is still sacred. It's part of
                        his life and part of his religion and so
                        long as he is an evangelist he will use
                        it in the Lord"? fight.
                        He told the crowd nt Dreamland rink
                        last night of his conversion how he
                        'got religion when h»> dreamed nothing
                        save stolen bapt-s and running catches.
                        He related how the Lord had called
                        him to. the new- fiiold and how he re
                        sponded. He told. of his trials and his
                        tribulations and his own temptations
                        and his struggles, and he fairly beamed
                        with happiness and joy when he in
                        formed his listeners that he is a better
                        fishter today than .tie was the day he
                        quit the diamond for the pulpit.
                        SINGLES SLAXG A. \D GOSPEL
                        There was many an old man and old
                        woman in that audience yesterday who
                        did not know half what Sunday was
                        telling them, but they could all see by
                        his earnest manner and the fervent
                        light in his oyes that he was "on the
                        square." as he put it. 'Tis so seldom
                        that a man who is preaching the word
                        of God searches the, diamond and the
                        streef for his' pet phrases that only the
                        up to date ones find themselves capable
                        Special Hlsrh Cln«* Party I2a«t
                        Leave San Francisco February 24 for
                        Washington, DC.; Baltimore, Philadel
                        phia., New York," Boston. See New Or
                        leans and inauguration Washington.
                        Lowest rates. Through cars. Write or
                        call at once. SJ4- Market street. Flood
                        building. P. K. Gordon. Agent Wash
                        inerton-Sunset Route.
                        Former Hero of Chicago Baseball
                        Fans Comes Here to Save Souls
                        Portrait of Billy Sunday, evangelist, who was a famous baseball; player, and two of his attitudes in exhorting
                        sinners to be: saved. \u25a0":'\u25a0: \u25a0;• v" \u25a0'._'- ''\u25a0''\u25a0'.. ':V...
                        of following Sunday as he spouts the
                        gospel and Billy Baxter in the same
                        phrases.
                        But this is Sunday's plan of cam
                        paign the successful plan which he
                        has followed for all these years
                        throughout the length and the breadth
                        of the land. He has found that it is a
                        winner for him one that "gives the
                        devil the best run for his money he
                        ever had." It strikes home, according
                        to the man \vho B has adopted it, and he
                        should be in a position to know, judg
                        ing from the thousands of converts
                        whom he has made since he quit base
                        ball.
                        One of the first men to greet Sunday
                        upon his arrival was William A. Lange,
                        a prominent real estate man of this
                        city, but known the country over as
                        "Little Eva" when he, with Sunday,
                        played on the great Chicago team. It
                        was the first time that these world re
                        nowned tossers had met in 20 years,
                        yet they knew each other at first
                        glance and fairly "jumped into an em
                        brace like ardent lovers, long sepa
                        rated.
                        OXCE FAMOUS PAIR MEET
                        "Well, Bill, old boy," exclaimed Sun
                        day, "you look like a man who has
                        prospered since you left poor old Pop
                        Anson and the rest of the gang back
                        in Chicago. How's the batting eye,
                        anyhow? It does me more good than
                        anything else to meet an old pal. like
                        you after all these years. Sit down
                        and tell me all about it."
                        Lange sat down and the famous pair
                        fanned and fanned over the happy, old
                        days. They -looked at each otheT like
                        a pair of youngsters starting to play
                        and they joked and laughed and talked
                        and played, ball over and over "again.
                        It was a moment of moments for them.
                        "Billy, I' want to thank you for put
                        ting me on that. everlasting All Ameri
                        can ball team," said Lange, referring
                        to a combination' of players which Sun
                        day named as the greatest that the
                        game has ever known or ever will
                        know.
                        "I know that you flattered me, and it
                        was a great honor. I. didn't think you
                        still remembered me."..
                        "Remember you.", blurted out Sunday.
                        "Do you think I could forget you?
                        You had the class in those days, old
                        boy. You could play the game and "hit
                        that ball when: a hit meant a run. I
                        never forget a ballplayer like you, Bill.
                        You're down on that everlasting. All
                        American ball team and none of them
                        have got.it on you either. You were
                        a ball player, you. were." _\u25a0'... :\u25a0/_
                        Then Sunday began- to dream of the
                        diamond and his wandered
                        back to those stirring times when' he
                        used to be: the .first .man _up..on that
                        mighty Chica-go- team." -The sight /of
                        Lange made 'him .think, of the others
                        who used to- be great, bu£ whom the
                        world has .forgotten now. \u0084
                        RECALL NOTED PLAYER
                        "Did you know .that, John Clarlcson
                        died the "other day back, in Massachu-'
                        setts?" inquired^" bystander. \u25a0
                        "John Clarkson> dead?" -asked^ Sun
                        day, as". lf .suddenly struck. VYou^don't
                        tell me. Ah, there is another sad. story,
                        the story of the greatest pitcher -who
                        ever. .threw '.'a> ball, over, a plate. Poor
                        old John. Booze and cigarettes got
                        him, and ju*t* in his- prime, too. He
                        couldn't see- the i evil^ of his J_way,- and
                        for the JastYf ew..; yearsj. his mind .was
                        a blank. Poor Clarkson!';
                        "And is old George/ Van Haitfen. still
                        in the game? "Well," well, I 'remember
                        Van 2a years ago back in the National
                        league, but" of late; I have lost track of
                        him. By \the"iway. you Caiiforniaris
                        turned out" some great ball players in
                        your day, and, you 'are still turning
                        them out; as' everybody, knows: who". has
                        heard of the fame^ of Overall .and
                        Chance. \u25a0 :\u25a0'-".•"'\u25a0\u25a0 \u25a0'".-.
                        .'Ti can go away back; and tell you
                        of lots, o\ them. 'Poor old Charley
                        Sweeney, :6ne 'eof the ''greatest- pitchers
                        of his .time,', "was from 'San,. Francisco,
                        too, but -he let the'devil in the form -of
                        whisky kill "him off. there were
                        Jerry Denny and v Carroll and Morris
                        and "White Wings' Patsy- Cahill—^H
                        from .your -Golden State 1 and" all /stars
                        when I. was in. the game. /\u25a0."::
                        "The. sight-of Bill Lange 'reminded
                        me of all these old 'timers. -Bill was
                        the greatest outfielder 1: ever, saw.- -We
                        were all proud of .him.. "It. was like" a
                        cure for-Eore eyes when I .spied. Bill
                        after all these years, we have, been sep
                        arated. ?>ow, I wish :I had conic to/San
                        Francisco before. Still,' I think.'that I
                        can do "my share \u25a0. toward casting the
                        devil out of your. midst, even during my
                        limited stay. Anyhow, I siiall try.
                        II A D WIDE EXPERIENCE
                        "I'm Just, as earnest an evangelist as
                        I wasa ball player'a" quarter of a-cen
                        tury, ago. "I'm for i saving souls .now
                        and bringing; ray: fellow, 1 men to; realize
                        as 1 realize that the way/of. Go

                        					<3 Js:the.
                        only way for any- of them.' /I have seen
                        more of this wicked life;, than /most
                        men. I have seen them 'come, and' go
                        and pass 'in and out, and" now* I know
                        that thY way of ;the Lord; is,the only
                        THE SAN ERANOISCQ vEBro^^^BRTJARY 12,; 1909;
                        way to travel. I know that. l. am on
                        the right path and I want them all to
                        get on the bases and run- around after
                        me. If they do, they will come home
                        and score for the honor of 'God and
                        not get left on the paths like the un
                        fortunates who live, without knowing
                        that the devil has them in his grip."
                        This is the way that the ball playing
                        disciple of the Lord talks. This is his
                        campaign, which he carefully mapped
                        out, and this is the way he .wants all
                        his fellow men to feel. He. believes
                        that everybody has a chance to live as
                        the Savior intended him to live and he
                        believes that he is one man among-men
                        who has been directed to preach the
                        word.
                        "Here is a letter from another fa
                        mous one of the bygone days, another
                        whom I had- all but forgotten," con
                        tinued the evangelist, as he tore open
                        a note from Dad Moulton, the beloved
                        trainer of the athletes of Stanford
                        university. "Do you know that it was
                        old Dad who trained. me for that fa
                        mous footrace I. ran against Arlie
                        Latham back in St. Louis in-the. early
                        eighties?" '-.v/' '\u25a0?'•\u25a0
                        WERE OLD TIME PALS
                        i "Dad and I were pals in those days.
                        I was one of the' best runners on the
                        Chicago team and Latham, poor fellow,
                        I don't know where he. is, now,. was the
                        star of the St. Louis Browns. .Well,
                        they matched us for a 100 yard-sprint
                        and Dad trained me and boosted jne
                        along. The race, was the event of .the,
                        season and I-.., wi1l modestly admit ;that
                        I beat Arlie in one of the- hottest. spurts
                        I ever made. Old Dad "won it:' for m e
                        and now after all these years. I- hope,
                        to. grasp his good right. hand and thank
                        him again." *w, '\u25a0'. '\u25a0\u25a0.'_'
                        During the course of; his;^ spell bind
                        ing oration at 1 Dreamland, Sunday -shot
                        a rapid fire volley, of; advice, criticism
                        and abuse-'at "his listeners that-seemed'
                        to awe every.; one -of them: He
                        nounced the average .\u25a0churchman7as be-
                        ing too 'full' of commercialism "to i\ pay'
                        any attention to God.':, He -roasted', and.
                        toasted society as a s^am and' a; farce,
                        and- he* said, he was*' "trying '/to^ make'
                        this old-world better-r-to make it easier
                        to go to heaven and. harder Po'^break
                        Into hell." •"•:;\u25a0\u25a0 '.\u25a0". \u0084' .-\u25a0: \u25a0-.'}} :_- "\u25a0.' ;".\u25a0
                        Sunday whipped "himself into a, fury.
                        His eyes- turned glassy" and he all -but
                        frothed :at the mouth.^-He danced
                        around'the stage,- took' his -coat- offhand
                        acted just like he used todonvhen.the'
                        bases were full and two .were outl^.iHe
                        took the crowd. by storm >"and the-iur-.
                        ther, he progressed the" more vehement
                        he became, .Probably* nobody^. In that,
                        vast audience \u25a0 .ever heard
                        quite" like It befpre in' the, evangelistic
                        line/; /'.\u25a0' r '\u25a0.' v; -..-•-I.
                        '."Judging^' from the "way. '.many -of
                        your church people act; youvwrould imf
                        agine.»that.' they had -ft -first ;classPullr
                        man- palace car ticket', to- the.; Al
                        mighty's jQaliri and that they, Jiad 'left
                        notice with" the' porter' hot to call, them,
                        'ti i\. Heaven was. reached,'.' thiindef ed
                        Sunday; ."but "most .of them; wakeJ up in
                        -tini«" to; realize.' that they-;" are "side
                        tracked" with/a .hot, box .and that- the
                        blgjtripis'all a jbke. \u25a0
                        Ki/aYS .RELIGIOUS SIIAMv
                        5 ."rm'.not a spiritual osteopath. ..I'm. a
                        surgeon';and every 1 time I "wield the
                        knifo". it 'goes .rightMrito the..' wou'ndvof
                        iniquity and j the stench and .corruption
                        cbm^out. Get together," all of yOu, ancl
                        shout^'AmTen!' now and. then. V Let .the
                        -"world know,;. that', .you. are.', not Y hide-'
                        bound.' -Half the itiembers^churches, cpuld j die; tomorrow. and the
                        churches Would not lose 'a. bit pf .their
                        spiritual force.; I BlOstf of /you' "are rob
                        bing God. There .are too .rnany..>men
                        keeping- their. storeS'^openlpn,- Sundaj'
                        arid passing^around -the collection .box
                        irif church. The "majority \u25a0of \u25a0-"•' us lack
                        enough; oil -to grease' one of the axles
                        of a ;wheel of God's chariot."
                        rThe".auSunday* at
                        his*, address last \u25a0 "evening,, was «.:e.ven
                        greater!, than thelafternoon! crowd,' and;
                        if "any thing, .the speaker t more
                        forcible^ and; earnest- than >on his -first
                        appearance. lie was roundly 'cheered
                        and.'the more the crowdrhurrahedHhe
                        more.{he rpjistcd and ;c6ndemried all
                        "hypociites and followers^ of the'devil."
                        Sunday; isaccbmpftn led Mel/Trot
                        ter, another. well known evangelist
                        wlio conducted. a* very.successful.revlval
                        her last year." ;\u25a0"' Sunday's; wi f e r and i four
                        children, ranging {frqmj a -babe- in; arms
                        to a /pretty- young jmissi/are "also in--'
                        eluded ;.iri> the. party," -which.w ill, leave
                        for. Los 'this af ternooTnA*;; \u0084:,".,
                        After,; a' few/lectures in 1 the; south
                        Sunday' wlU'returWeast

					</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85052114/1909-02-27/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=billy+sunday&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.884,-0.074,2.769,1.377,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>A Sunday better known as Billy
                        Sunday former baseball playernow
                        an evangelist waft horsewhipped
                        by a man at tho Sunday Taber
                        nacla where In tho presence of
                        SVMO persons he wan conducting tho
                        opening meeting of n revival
                        The evangelist had just made his
                        opening remarks and was leaning
                        against the pulpit on tho elevated
                        platform white If hymn was sung by
                        his tholpearler when II man who said I
                        his name was Sherman Pttttt sprang
                        otwardlwltha buggy whip and struck
                        Sunday Jevernl terrific blows
                        Siinilay Girl Ihttllo
                        Sunday leaped I from the platform
                        and dashed at his assailant whom he
                        knocked down In the center of the
                        aisle The audience was on the verge
                        of panic with women weeping and
                        children screaming while Potts and
                        Sunday rolled and ti tnbled In tho
                        aisle The choir and the audience
                        however continued to sing and quiet
                        was soon restored Several men seiz
                        ed Potts and they held him until a
                        policeman came and tookhlm to Jail
                        The prisoner said his homo was
                        near Lovlngton 111 According to hid
                        statements at the jail he was onco
                        declared Insane and committed to the
                        Jacksonville asylum whenco after d
                        brief confinement he was released as
                        cured He said he came to Spring
                        field from Efecatur today to horsewhip
                        Sunday that he had purchased the
                        whip In I Springfield and went to the
                        tabernacle early He made the at
                        tack ho said Iri I defense of the virtue
                        of a woman which he declared had
                        been criticized 1 y the evangelist
                        The police say Potts Is a religious
                        fanatic</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1909-07-04/ed-1/?sp=41&amp;q=billy+sunday&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.462,-0.047,1.849,0.92,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Sunday i h is of the opinion o1 lnlol1 that tho hasbeens hasbeenswore hnsboonsworo hasbeenswore
                        wore equally is a groat In their day Modesty would wouldnaturally wouldnnturnlly wouldnaturally
                        naturally cause him to eliminate himself from any anyof anyof anyof
                        of tho comparisons but in speaking of tho old olddays olddays llddnys
                        days Sunday said saidTho saidTho saidThe
                        Tho individual ball player of today ia no hotter hotterthan bottoIUmn bettorthan
                        than ho was twenty or twentyfive years ago In Infact Infnot Infact
                        fact I believe that taking everything overy thing into consid consideration consldorntlon considoration
                        oration the follows of a quarter of a century ago agooxcollod ngoCxoollod agogxcollod
                        oxcollod in some ways To bo true what a man mandoos mand008
                        doos nowadays counts for more In a game for fornow fornow fornow
                        now they have team work down to perfection In Intho Inthe Inthe
                        the old days we hardly know what toam work workas worlea workas
                        as a the word applies today was Wo know noth nothing nothIng nothing
                        ing about a hit and run game or tho doublo steal stealthat stoalthat stealthat
                        that was all unknown dope to us Consoquently Consequentlyplaying Consoquentlynlqylng Consoquentlyplaying
                        playing moro as individuals more rested on us an anindividuals a aindividuals asindividuals
                        individuals Hence my reason for saying that thatperhaps thatwlmps thatperhaps
                        perhaps wlmps in some ways tho boys or the old days daysQxoollod daysQxOolloa dayagxcolled
                        Qxoollod tho stars of today todayLearned todnyLearned todayLearned
                        Learned the Game In Cow Lot Lotof LotA LotLITTLIO
                        A LITTLID history of Dilly Sundays adoption adoptionof
                        of a baseball career will bo interesting to tho thoolder thoohIoI theolder
                        older fans who remember woll tho old days or An Anon Anlon Anson
                        lon on and Clarkson and tho immortal Kelly Pro Professional Prorosslonal Profossional
                        fessional baseball with Billy Sunday was more moroof moreOf moreof
                        of an accident than otherwise and his career may mayh mnyh
                        h attributed solely to Cap Anson An SOil who round found1him roundI foundhim
                        I him himIn himIn him
                        In tho early 80B Billy Sunday was brought to
                        Marshalltown by manag managers mannsers managera
                        ers of o a volunteer hose hoseteam hosotonm hoseteam
                        team In those days lire liremens 11remens firemens
                        mens tournaments wore woreamong worgnmong wereamong
                        among the big events ovon ts of ofthe ortho ofthe
                        the year and commanded commandedwldo commandedwldo commandedwlde
                        wldo interest Sunday Sundaywas Sundaywas Sundaywas
                        was then a youth living livingat livIngat livingat
                        at Nevada Iowa tho thocounty thocounty thecounty
                        county seat of Story his hisnative hlHnatlvo hisnative
                        native county Sunday Sundaywas SundaywaB Sundaywas
                        was fleet of foot o a tho thohose thoh080 thehose
                        hose team managers were werelooking werelooking werelooking
                        looking for just his kind kindThey lelndThoy kindThey
                        They secured a job for forhim 101him forhim
                        him in n Marshalltown in inorder Inordor inorclor
                        order to get him on the thetaam thetoam theteam
                        team Sunday was then thenrunning thenrunning thenrunning
                        running easily In 10J4 10J4naturally 10112naturally 1O1 1O1naturally
                        naturally ho was a valu valuable valunblo valuable
                        able man manIncidentally manIncldentnlly manIncidentally
                        Incidentally Sunday Sundayliked Sun S u n day daylIkod d a y yliked
                        liked to play ball and he hewas 11ewas liewas
                        was out in n tho pasture for forpractice fornrnctlco forpractico
                        practice regularly He be began bogan began
                        gan to command atten attention attenUon attention
                        tion in this line not so somuch somuch somuch
                        much for his proficiency proficiencyin
                        in tho game as his fleet
                        ness of foot and his great greatbaso greatbaao greatbase
                        base running Ho was a awonder awandoI awonder
                        wonder for his day and andIt andIt andtt
                        It was practically a cinch cinchwhen cinchWhOll cinchwhen
                        when he got a base that thatwith thatwIth thatwith
                        with any kind of luck at atII
                        II
                        1
                        Sunday quit olmilng ohnsingbnsebai olmilngbnnoball ahahllIJ1tobnll
                        bnnoball lllou to chase chasethe olma olmathe 0110 0110tho
                        the dovil ha linn hu boon boontromondouily boontlom boontromndously
                        tromondouily tlom ntloully b u I IIllonchhll y ypreaching ypronching
                        preaching tho gospoland gospolandsaving gospol and andsaving findIllvlna
                        saving tho gouts of toni toniof ton tonor tonsof
                        of thousand of mon and andwomen nil nilwomOll andwomon
                        women ho is still nthoroughbred n nthoroughbrad ntholOUflhblol
                        thoroughbred fan arid aridthoro ftrulthoro andthere
                        thoro Isnt a devotee of oftho ortho ofthe
                        tho groat national game gameanywhoro gnmcltIywhoro gameunywhoro
                        anywhoro who loops ItOOI in incloaor InlaHar incloser
                        closer touch with it than thanho thanho thanho
                        ho Of courgo there theroare thorouro thereare
                        are days dny when this thisformergreat thiaformorgroat till tilltormorglont
                        formorgroat ball play playor pla plaer playor
                        or haint limo to fan fanbut funbut fanbut
                        but ono day of every ovoryseven overyhovon everyaevon
                        seven is a rest day with withhim withhim withhim
                        him and on that day
                        R o d Clarke Cl ar k e Wells W e 11 S trnto tra To tho lllus lllustrnto 111U8o dlf
                        nil ho would tally a nl tho fans thon said It USo ItSo itEgo
                        So Sunday made hi his debut with tho i Marshall Marshalltown Mnr 1arshalltown haU haUtown
                        town tonm tonmIl a strong amateur bunch for thoia thoiailnya thOIHJriA thosoclays
                        clays riA Marahalltown In 1882 had beaten everything everythingit
                        it had played with the exception of tho team of oftho otlho ofthe
                        the Capital City and that it had not played Like Likewise 104110wllo Likewise
                        wise Dos Moinoa had won all its It I games nmol and the theresult thorOllult therosult
                        result was a contest conto t for tho championship champlon hlp of Iowa IowaSunday lownSunday IowaSunday
                        Sunday played loft Hold In the game which was waspullod wnapul10d waspulled
                        pulled off in Dos Moines Mnrshnlltown Ma18hullt vll won 11 11to Hto 14to
                        to 0 Tho young man Sunday so distinguished distinguishedhimaolf dltlngulshodhlmloU distinguishedhimself
                        himself by making makln several hits nnd scores that thatPop thltPop thathop
                        Pop Ansons AnMon attention was called to him when whenAnson whonAnBon whenAnson
                        Anson camo out to Marshalltown Mnr halltown tho noxt winter winterto wlntolto winterto
                        to visit his father Anion looked Sunday up and andmade ntu ntumado andmade
                        made him a proposition Tho result was that Sun Sunday Sunday Sunday
                        day wont to Chicago in tho spring of 1883</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1915-02-26/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=billy+sunday+circus&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.379,0.027,1.81,0.9,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Pitre hundred members of the Amer?
                        ican Wine Growers' Association loudly
                        applauded the Rev. William A. Wasson
                        last night at their annual dinner in
                        the Waldorf. There were a few huses
                        when the retired Fpiscopal clergyman,
                        who said he left the pulpit to preach
                        real temperance against the so-called
                        temperance of prohibition, assailed
                        Billy Sunday and reformers.
                        "?some of the people of this country
                        aro problemanlacs," said Dr. Wasson,
                        "who are possessed with the delusion
                        that they must solve certain problem!
                        to save the nation. They meddle with
                        the morals of other people. They think
                        they can make everybody good by their
                        own standards and they work them
                        selvea into a state of frenzy over it.
                        "We see a striking illustration in th??
                        Billy Sunday circus exhibited in Phila?
                        delphia these last few weeks. Billy
                        Sunday A a true leader of the type of
                        men I have Fpecitied. He is called a
                        true leader, but be shows only evi?
                        dences of religious insanity. His con?
                        verts believe they have found religion,
                        tiut really they have lost their mental
                        balanoe.
                        "I he best I can say of Billy Sunday
                        and his methods or his religion is that
                        they are on a dead level with Billy
                        Sunday himself. To my mind he is a
                        very cheap and vulgar sensationalist."
                        Hiram S. Dewey, president of the as?
                        sociation, was the toastmaster. Among
                        those present was a whole tab!? ot
                        Dewey?, George F... (ieorge .F., William
                        I!., Ralph C. and Seth B. Dewey.
                        others were Sheriff Grifenhagen, Mar?
                        tin Bourke, Thomas F. Carmody, for?
                        mer Attorney General; Justice Freschi,
                        of Special Sessions; Henry Heller, Gen?
                        eral H. I). Hamilton, Kdward Lauter?
                        bach, Joseph P. MeCann, John V. Mc
                        Avoy, Theodore Rousseau, Professor
                        Jame i M. Washburne. Samuel S. Koenig
                        and William I!. Alwood.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1915-04-15/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=billy+sunday&amp;st=image&amp;r=0.148,0.272,1.009,0.502,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Si rred to
                        higbeat enthusiasm b;
                        Mia- Billy Sunday be called to K
                        land ??i conduct ;he great national b
                        tie for prohibition. _ eon
                        Great Britain's mont prominent bl
                        ness men united to-day ,11 call
                        th? evangelist to come h"- and 0|
                        his campaign in Ho?, a'
                        April 27.
                        Late thi? aften,.? Henry I
                        ward Randall, hn md'a greatest si
                        manufacturer ano chairman of I
                        Business Men' ?nipaign for Prohi
                        tion in England, sent the follow-i
                        cable:
                        "Billy Suiiilay, care New Yi
                        Tribune, New 'i
                        "Belie-e you could win prohibit
                        for Great Britain. The country
                        ready. Quarter of a million appe
                        have b? 11 lfceived by D?
                        George. Chancellor of ti e E_cha*]U
                        We propose ?tatting you;- campaign
                        'Albert Hall on April 27. Th? K lg
                        Queen would probably attend. Stro
                        i business men are behind this niov
                        ment. All the receipts would go to yi
                        le-.? the organization expenses.
                        "RANDALL.'
                        Plan lo Aid War.
                        No recent development of the war
                        and this must be regarded as a big w
                        de- elopment has so aroused ment
                        and physical activity among F.nglanc
                        industrial and government lea?lers
                        this move, which is desisrned to ta'
                        ii oui the grip of aicohol the thouaan
                        of workmen engaged in making Wi
                        supplies for the Allies. Their iiuln
                        gence in liquor has so retarded pr
                        duction thai treat. Britain fears i
                        war success ia threatened unless Sui
                        day, hy his personal contact campa in
                        pulls them away from drinking ar
                        fires them with a pa ol il m
                        speed up their work.
                        Soon after ihe London eo tspondei
                        of The Tribune had informed Heni
                        Randall that the latter'? appi
                        Tuesday had been cabled to Th
                        un? m New fork ami then eommun
                        caled to Sunday. Sir Henry got inl
                        touch with Sir WiHiani rleekcth Lev?
                        chairman of Lever Brothei?, 1
                        makera of si.hp. and Angus Watsoi
                        another captain of industry, and th
                        tiiree men were soon in conferenei
                        It wh? readily agreed 'hat in 3
                        lay the one hone of converting th
                        -luggish workmen to prohibition an
                        ie?ultant activity.
                        The conference consumed ?hi?
                        hours. After it had been decid?
                        a call was to be sent tu the evangelist
                        Sir Henry, Sir William and Mr. Wal
                        ??.n communicated by telephone an.
                        telegraph with all the principal
                        and towns throughout Great Britain
                        securing options on the largest hall
                        in these place?. The?? op'ions cove
                        dates in the near future.
                        To evidence the enthusiasm and OC
                        livity whii'h have seued the promoter
                        of the movement, it need onlv be san
                        that a tentative tour programme ha
                        already heen drawn up, and Sundav'i
                        refu??! tn entertain the pruposit im
                        ?ould effect a tremendous shock.
                        "We believe this is the psychologies
                        fnoment when a man like Sunday coul?
                        convince the people of this countrv
                        that prohibition is the only way out
                        'he only way to ?uecea? for the Al
                        Sir Henry said after the o i
                        i.e.
                        "If he '.?.ill ??mie over here he will
                        expei ience no trouble in a financial
                        senM. The money is already at hand
                        W'e would hire the biggest halls in
                        every city and town in Urea* Britain
                        lor him. Included in our committee
                        are the country's greatest captains of
                        industry. Big business men every?
                        where will back ?he movement.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093039/1916-08-18/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=billy+sunday&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.612,0.329,1.758,0.874,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Hood River, Ore. Billy Bunday,
                        whose evangelistic sermons hare been
                        heard by ;it least b million p<
                        the coarae <>f year, never w i the
                        conventional frock of tbe minister, but
                        just now may lie seen at almost any
                        hour between dawn mid twiii-'ht.
                        dressed In brogans, overalls, khaki
                        jh' kot and slouch hat, engaged In the
                        labor of .-i rancher at the Hood river
                        ralley country borne of the Sundays in
                        the Odell district. It is "Farmer" Sun
                        day now, if you rlonse. and Mr. Sun
                        Jay always dresses the part.
                        Hilly Sunday and "Ma," his faithful
                        coworker, with two of their children,
                        Billy Junior and Paul, recently arrived
                        for a vacation sojourn on the ranch.
                        Billy Sunday, whoso first fame came
                        from Ids aggressive baseball playing as
                        '■1 fir W\ §m
                        Photo by American I'ress Association.
                        BILLS SUNDAY IB NOW I'UTTIXO SOME OP
                        HIS FAMOt'B POSES INTO FAUMINij.
                        a member of the Chicago White Pox
                        team In the late eighties, for the time
                        being has apparently forgotten base
                        ball und evangelism. The caller nt the
                        Odell place on a summer day will Qnd
                        Mr. and Mrs. Sunday out In the open
                        nlr weeding flowers, picking berries,
                        helping with the hay. opening rills of
                        Irrigation ditches, watching the antics
                        of pigs or ponies or engaged In some
                        sort of open air game.
                        When the writer, accompanying the
                        Rev. W. B. Young, pastor of the As
                        lmry Methodist church of this city, and
                        his wife, visited the Sunday home Mrs.
                        Sunday was picking red raspberries
                        and currants, which were being made
                        into delicious sun cooked preserves and
                        Jellies.
                        "Our jellies," Mrs. Sunday said, "are
                        lust as good as the choicest confec
                        tions."
                        Sunday was soon located, and he
                        told liis visitors while he kept hoeing
                        that the pine ir laden air renews his
                        strength.
				</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1916-08-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=billy+sunday&st=image&r=-0.496,0.235,1.749,0.87,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Billy Sunday, full of his old-tlma pep,
                        brcozed Into Philadelphia today, and nftcr
                        n short stay ot two hours, was whirled
                        away oceanward, eager to carry the fight
                        to the cabarets nnd liquor shops which have
                        been reported aa 'flourishing" in Asbury
                        Park almost within a stone's throw of
                        Ocean Groio, whero ho opens a 10-day
                        revival tonight.
                        "I have no definite Information as to tho
                        extent of theso scourges of Bin In Asbury
                        Park," tho evangelist said today. 'But you
                        can bet your bottom dollar that I'll tackle
                        them, lick and wallop them Just as hard as
                        In any other placo I've been. Meanwhile
                        I'm glad to sco the old faces, tho old
                        friends In Old Philly again."
                        Accompanied by "Ma" Sunday and Alba
                        B. Johnson, president of the Baldwin Loco
                        motive Works, with whom ho came from
                        New York, "Billy" arrived at Broad Street
                        Station at 11 o'clock. In record-breaking
                        time he was whirled nvvay in tho automo
                        bllo of Joseph M. Steele to the Bellevue
                        Stratford, where nearly 100 admirers. In
                        cluding many from Trenton, Patcrson and
                        Baltimore, pressed forward to give him </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1918-12-26/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=Billy+Wilbur+Chapman&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.541,0.763,0.242,0.241,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>He wns associated with "Billy" Sunday
                        upon numerous occasions and know hlni prob.
                        ably better than any ono except "Ilill's"
                        wife, he often said. In an Interview concern
                        ing his friendship and stowardshlp for Sun
                        day, he said
                        "1 know 'Hilly' beforo ho knew bow to
                        pray I gave him his first sermon, and
                        It was a fatal thing to do, because I could
                        nover use It again. I tried to uso It onco
                        nnd a man accused me of stenllng 'Billy's
                        ctuff. I, perhaps, am moro responsible than
                        any one clsu for 'Billy' becoming a prencher,
                        and 1 consider It tho greatest thing (Jod ever
                        permitted mo to do. I know him better, prob
                        ably, than any one else except his wife, and
                        I know how honest, how sincere and how
                        great he really Is."
                        This personal Interest seemed to be char
                        acteristic of DoLtor Chapman, for ho took
                        an exceedingly fond Inteiest In many men
                        and their ptrsona! affairs.
                        Doctor Chapman carried this personal
                        touch Into his evangelistic work. Slany aro
                        the etorles of his personal solicitation winning
                        recruits for the Church.
                        Beginning his pastorate at Bethany in 1890,
                        ho left after a few jears to engage In evan
                        gelistic work, going on a tour which took
                        him to many sections of tho country. He re.
                        turned to this city In 1890 to resume his
                        pastorato at Bethany Church, continuing
                        there until 1900, when he uccepted a call to
                        the Fourth Presbyterian Church, New York.
                        Doctor Chapman resembled a successful busi
                        ness man, rather than a preacher, and he
                        prenrhed with an Intense earnestness which
                        commanded the, respectful nttcntlon of men
                        and women everywhere Thousands Joined
                        the Church as a result of his preaching He
                        delivered addresses nt meetings In cities from
                        tho Atlantic to the Pacific, and always nt
                        tincted big audiences.
                        Ho waH elected Moderator of tho 129tb
                        Clcneial Assembly In May, 1917. this being
                        the highest honor the Presbyterian Church
                        can bestow upon ono of Its ministers
                        As executive secretary of tho ffeneral As
                        sembly's Committee on Uvnngellstlc Work,
                        nnd representatlve-at-large of tho Commis
                        sion on Kvangellsm, Doctor Chapman gave
                        great Impetus to the evangelistic activities of
                        the Presbyterian Church. At one time, ht
                        organized missionary parties for Australia
                        and other countries.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062014/1935-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Billy+Evangelist&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.048,0.716,0.659,0.656,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>“Billy” Sunday,
                        72, evangelist, died here sud
                        denly Wednesday night of
                        angina pectoris at the home
                        of William J. Thompson, a
                        brother-in-law.
                        He came to Chicago Sunday
                        from Winona Lake, Indiana,
                        with his wife and stayed at
                        the Thompsons. He went up
                        stairs shortly before eight o’
                        clock complaining of illness.
                        He died before a physician
                        arrived.
                        Billy Sunday suffered his
                        first attack of illness three
                        years ago at DesMoines. His
                        widow said he had a severe
                        heart attack last May. Mean
                        while he had attempted to
                        keep up his revival work but
                        his strength waned steadily
                        during the summer.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1918-01-15/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Sunday+Evangelist&amp;r=0.341,0.024,0.693,0.345,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Students of th? Thompson and Frank
                        lin schools met today at the Church of
                        the Ascension to hear Miss Miriam
                        Qamlln, director of the Billy Sunday
                        evangelistic work among boys and
                        girls, talk on the Bible message to
                        children.
                        Miss Gamlin, who accompanies the
                        Billy Sunday party in Its trips, has her
                        own record cf trail hitters. Not, it is
                        true, as large as that of Billy himself,
                        but the youngsters whom Miss Gamlin
                        converts have started In the path led
                        by their elders, who are privileged to
                        hear the evangelist.
                        Miss Gamlin, in conducting a aeries
                        of Bible lectures in connection with
                        the Sunday campaign, Is oarrylng the
                        message of the Bible to the sohool
                        children of Washington, who are not
                        allowed in the Tabernacle.
                        The program of meetings for the
                        week follows: Tomorrow, Webster
                        School students will meet at the First
                        Congregational Church at 3:15. MisS
                        Gamlin will address parents at the
                        same church at 7:45 p.m. Thursday,
                        pupils of the Blake School will meet
                        at the North Capitol Methodist Church
                        at 3:15 p.m.. Friday, students at Bar
                        rett, Adams and Dennison schools and
                        the Protestant Orphan Asylum will
                        j meet at the Foundry Methodist Church,
                        on 16th street, at 3:15. There will be a
                        meeting of the parents in the Emory
                        Methodist Episcopal Church, 6100 Geor
                        gia avenue, in the evening.
                        Miss Gamlin addressed a number of
                        I Washington. Sunday school superln
                        I tendents and teachers at a meeting at
                        the First Congregational Church last
                        night on co-operation of Sunday schools
                        with the Billy Sunday campaign. BILLY SUNDAY DIDNT
                        PREACHDAYSERMQN
                        Evangelist Troubled With
                        Hoarseness?To Be on Job
                        Again Tonight.
                        "BACKSLIDERS," HIS TOPIC
                        Dr. Ward in Sunday's Place.
                        Dr. Isaac Ward, Billy Sunday**
                        assistant, will speak In place of
                        the evangelist at this afternoon's
                        meeting.
                        The evangelist will prraob on
                        "Backsliders" at this evening's
                        services at 7:S0 o'olook.
                        Tonight will be business wom
                        en's night. Reservations have
                        been made for 5,000.
                        Billy Sunday did not preach at this
                        afternoon's service In the Tabernacle.
                        When tho evangelist arose this morn*
                        inr his voice was so hoarse that he
                        was advised by his physician not to
                        take part in the two services.
                        He will be back on the job, however,
                        at this evening's meeting. He will
                        preach on "Backsliders."
                        In place of Ur. Sunday Dr. Isaac
                        Ward, his assistant, occupied the plat
                        form this afternoon. It was thought
                        beet for the evangelist to save his
                        energies for tonight.</text>
      		</result>
      		<result>
      			<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1922-12-30/ed-1/?sp=16&amp;q=Chicago+White+Stockings+Billy+Sunday&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.056,-315.463,1.111,632.222,0</id>
      			<rel>1</rel>
      			<text>SPEED was the greatest individu
                        less foe of Satan and booze, w
                        list, dre\v_semi-monthiy pas- em
                        ,t?Ke Tti*. r>i time verv often r
                        t originally docs not possess. Perha
                        greater credit as a player than he t
                        iveragc of .257 would not entitle hin
                        ;wat in this series but for the man
                        Satan.
                        But Billy rehearsed his prescn
                        National League competition. Like
                        >f the great speed boys after him, he
                        nee he got on the bases he ran as tl
                        inderworld were on his trail.
                        Stolen base records were not kept
                        n Sunday's early years in the Na- i
                        ional League, but his stolen ba.se j
                        tverage for the last five years of his
                        tight seasons in the National League
                        urnish a pretty good idea on how i
                        le could flit around the base paths,
                        le stole 258 bases in 388 games, an
                        tverage of .063 per game.
                        Sunday showed a burst of speed
                        vith the Pirates and Phillies in his;
                        ast season as a professional ball
                        layer, stealing 96 bases in 116 games.
                        Ind lie (lid it" on a naiuns average j
                        >f .265: Ty Gofrb stole 58 bases In j
                        915. but lie did it in 156 games and
                        n a batting average of .370.
                        Incidentally 1890. Sunday's last year j
                        n the National League, was his best.
                        le did hit .359 in forty-eight games
                        or the W hite Stockings in 1S87, but
                        Jilly hit over his head that year, as
                        t was his only batting average .beter
                        than ,265.
                        I once asked" John K. Tener, a team
                        nate of Sunday's in Chicago, what
                        :ind of a ball player Billy was.
                        "Sunday was a good ball player. I
                        ?ut riot a great one," replied the for-
                        ner governor. "He never played reg- j
                        ilarly on the old Chicago White J
                        itockings because he couldn't hit
                        onsistently when played every day.
                        >ut he was a mighty useful fellow
                        hiLVA sittinsr on the bench and al
                        rays dangerods on the bases.
                        Just the same Sunday had one of
                        ils red letter days against Teper
                        rhlle playing with the Pirates In</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1906-04-15/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=Baseball+Billy+Sunday&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.267,-0.077,1.534,1.534,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Billy Sunday Is Making Money as an
                        Evangelist.
                        From the New York Telegraph.
                        Evangelism that pays is the new force
                        In the world of religious work, introduced
                        into it by Rev. William A. Sunday, the
                        “ball piaytng evangelist,” who once
                        0printed Ground the diamond for the
                        Chicago National league team.
                        According to the available figures on
                        the work of Rev. Mr. Sunday, and the
                        coincident “free will” offerings of the
                        thousands who Jiavo flocked to his reviv
                        als in Illinois. Iowa, and Minnesota ho
                        gets an average of >2.1G 2-3 for every soul
                        he saves.
                        The figures may be deceptive, but it is
                        certain that the former baseball player
                        draws thousands to the “mourners’
                        bench” by the force of his rugged oratory
                        and that thousands of dollars pour into
                        the collection baskets on the last night
                        Of each revival, when an “offering” is
                        taken for the evangelist.
                        That it pays better than baseball—even
                        the high-class baseball Billy Sunday used
                        to draw a big salary for—Is shown by this
                        table of figures, collected In the towns in
                        which the evangelist has labored since
                        October, 1905:
                        Offerings to
                        Evangelist
                        Conversions Sunday
                        Aledo, 111.1.000 >3,000
                        Burlington, Towa.2,600 *1.000
                        Rochester, Minn .1.S00 2,400
                        Princeton, 111.2,600 6,000
                        Totals..7.800 $16,000
                        These amounts Is should be rememberer,
                        do not by any means represent the totals
                        of the collections during the revivals,
                        which last from three to five weeks in the
                        various towns. These sums are merely
                        what Evangelist Sunday himself collects
                        on the closing night of each series of
                        meetings, and which by a rigid contract
                        with the ministers’ association in each
                        town belongs to Rev Mr. Sunday.
                        Just a year ago at the close of a stirring
                        series of revivals that ended In a burst of
                        glory at Dixon, 111., when the whole Rock
                        River valley was aflame with religious en
                        tlmiasm stirred up by the old sprinter and
                        baseball player, lie claimed to have estab
                        lished the following record of conversions:</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-bat-masterson</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93061631/1881-04-20/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+Cowboy+shootout&amp;r=-0.223,0.596,1.12,0.557,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Bat Masterson, Peacock
                        aud a man named Updrufi" were the
                        principals, lhe cause was a pnvat
                        quarrel and whisky. Over twenty
                        mots were Ired in the street
                        m the business part o
                        the town. Updrufi was shot through
                        the lungs but. possibly he may recov
                        cr. Muatcrson and his party, who
                        started the row, were allowed to cs
                        cape thereby avoiding prosecution
                        As vet no ellorts have beeu made to
                        capture him. It is said that he ha
                        been in this city since the shooting.
                        There were mimerours rumos curren
                        ou the streets la6t night stating that
                        Bat Masterson had been killed in
                        Dodge Citv. Numerous other men
                        were reported killed or wounded
                        The above special despatch was re
                        ceived at a late hour last night from
                        the Pueblo Chieftain in response to
                        au inquiry from this office as to what
                        had happened in Dodge City. We
                        were unable to reach Dodge by tele
                        graph but presume this is the lates
                        from that place.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85030221/1883-05-24/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+Cowboy&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.052,0.835,0.642,0.319,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The city
                        is quiet, but fermenting. The- sheriff,
                        George T. ilinkel, by order of the gov.
                        ernor, met the 11 o'clock train with flf
                        ty armed men t protect Luke Short
                        and companion, which was understood
                        to be the famous Bat Masterson, form
                        erly sheriff of ihis county, but now out
                        lawed cy the city officers. There is no
                        doubt but that Air. (short will return
                        lie and his paitnur, ait. uarris, nave a
                        large caule interest, also a large saloon
                        which enipljys twen'.y-eight men, and
                        flains ia vice president of the Dodge
                        City bink. Reports furnished
                        the Capital are to the tffoct
                        that there is a strong fteliog that
                        Short should not be permitted to return.
                        The marshal of the city, Jack Bridges,
                        famous as a fighter and a fair man, says
                        he is as much the marshal tor one party
                        a-s the other. The indications show the
                        city authorities to be weakening and
                        thai the law will prevail. The governor
                        t:l-gC'ths thM. the la-v iuumI b- eni'.rc
                        ed una Hie rights id Me and property
                        protected. A company at Sterling are
                        awaiting orders, whiie the other side
                        talk of la&king a light. A committee
                        composed of Hon. O VV. llooyer, repre
                        sentative, Hon. R. M. Wright, Air. Bee
                        son arid Dr. Gxliand left to interview
                        Governor Giick .yesterday morning.
                        Nothing his txren heard since then. The
                        sheriff is on guard at the trains. with a
                        posse.
                        Kass City. MivH-Luke Short,
                        the Dodge Ci'y t xile, 1. frlorToH-kathis
                        morning, eccomriauloti by Bat Master,
                        son, expet-.ling to meet other ot bis
                        friends and confer with them thire.
                        While not inclined to talk much, he
                        seems inclined tnp-rott-t in his intention
                        of returning to Dodge, nlitiouiih urged
                        by bis friends t deter it f r a time Ii
                        bndeterniics to go from Topk. lie
                        will not b-j liktly to leave there baton-to-morrow.
                        Topeka. May 16. Several pani-v
                        from Dodge Uuy are here, who gy that
                        Short will be allowed to return In a
                        few days. Hs is here -and will remain
                        three-or four days and then return but
                        just under what circumstances be dnrs
                        oot-know. Ue says he doesn't wish to
                        be received by a party of depu'y sher
                        iffs, because bv knows m tny of t'ti-m to
                        be bis enemies. Bat Masterson is here
                        with him, but whether he will accom
                        pany Short when he rttnrna is not de
                        cided. It Is believed there will be do
                        trouble.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84029838/1883-11-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+Cowboy&amp;r=0.074,0.021,0.661,0.329,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Bat Masterson.
                        Cot Bat Masterson, swell known
                        character is the west, has discarded his
                        former illegitimate business and has
                        adopted newspaper writing as a pro
                        fession. While Col. Masterson's liter
                        ary effusioBS do not have moral or re
                        ligious tendencies, they are chaste pro
                        ductions in a literary way. The fine
                        artistic style in which CoL Bat wields
                        the pen is adding fame to his already
                        illustrious name. Col. Masterson is
                        now associate editor of the Ford
                        County Globe, and the last number of
                        that paper bears ample evidence oT this
                        statement The Globe has long need
                        ed a brainy editor, and the substitution
                        of brains for adipose tissue is certainly
                        commendable, and must be highly ap
                        preciated by the readers of that journal.
                        As a newspaper writer Bat is gaining
                        distinction.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1887-03-13/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+Cowboy&amp;r=0.082,-0.004,0.862,0.429,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>An El Paso Tex. correspondent says
                        When Luke Short a bad man with n
                        record shot Jliri Courtwright another
                        bad man with n record at Fort Worth
                        recently ho reduced the professional
                        killers of the west to a quartet. The list
                        stands at present in order of precedence
                        Bat Masterson.DocHolliday Luke Short
                        and Wyatt Earp. There used to bo more
                        juttlie same wise Providence that disin-
                        ccratcd the Jesse James gang and di
                        .rlbutcd it among the cemeteries ueni-
                        cntlarics and dime museums of the land
                        la elected that bad men eventually kill
                        each other. Thus the supply has been
                        ept ahead of the demand. The interest
                        hat attaches to those men is purely trans-
                        lory a dead killer is as quickly forgotten
                        is a knocked-out pugilist but the quali
                        ties of nerve and desperation that brought
                        them to the surface in a country where
                        everybody carries u "gun" and people
                        GO TO OLOItr EVERY DAY
                        without a benediction or a bootjack
                        stamps them as rather extraordinary
                        characters. Bat Mastorson first became
                        border celebrity through this paper in
                        which a correspondent rehearsed his
                        pcdmree some years ago. Since that
                        imc inure lias been written about him
                        than all the other three put together. He
                        is the Maud S. of man killers. Nobody
                        das ever lowered his record but he
                        claims that the twcnty-siv or twenty-
                        seven inmates of his private graveyard
                        were all sent thither in pursuit of his
                        dutv as an otliecr. All his lifi has been
                        spent on the frontier. He was lir t a
                        cowboy then a scout in the United
                        States employ and afterward marshal
                        in several western town notablv Dodge
                        City Kansas and Tnmulad Colorado.
                        Personally Masterson is the best extant
                        specimen of the gentleman desperado
                        copyrighted by Bret Harto. He has
                        trained the voice that erstwhile
                        YELLED TOR COWS
                        down to a low gentle baritone he al
                        ways dresses in black wears no jewelry
                        save a slender gold thread of a watch
                        chain a white cambiic handkerchief
                        peeps from the breast pocket of his four-
                        button cutaway and he is carcfuj about
                        Ills boots and ties. A friend who invaded
                        Ins room when he was here recently
                        found tvyo six-shooters and a manicure
                        sot on his bureau. Ho never blu.sters.
                        hen lie gets mad his mustache croons
                        up under his nose in a peculiar smile
                        that has no merriment in it and ho
                        reaches for his revolver which he car
                        ries thrust in the waistband of his
                        "pants directly under the lower but
                        tons of his vest. It looks like the irony
                        of fate that such a man should gravitate
                        into a theatrical /husband. Such how
                        ever was tho'jdestiny of Mastcrson. Not
                        long since he ma'rr.ed JScllio McMahon
                        a western .soubrotte and now he carries
                        the pug and "wears fur on his overcoat
                        collar. Mrs. 'Mastcrson nee McMahon
                        is not troubled with mashers.
                        DOC HOLLIDAY WAS A DF.NTIST
                        at Tombstone Arizona before lie be
                        came a killer. When he gave up the
                        forceps for the Six-shooter his old pa
                        tients said it was simply a change of
                        method. The glare of publicity first
                        struck him in 188U in an article in Har
                        per's Monthly descriptive of a trip
                        through the territories and detailing in
                        connection a street tracredy at Tomb
                        stone. At tho'timo a deadly feud existed
                        there between the gambling fraternity
                        and the cowboys. When killings were a
                        matter of almost daily occurrence a
                        long lean man with a straw-colored
                        moustache and a facile six-shooter sud
                        denly bloomed out as a leader of the
                        sports. This was Doc Holiiday. He
                        killed three or four cowboys and his
                        careless indifference to danger made
                        liim conspicuous even amoiitr his dare
                        devil associates. He did not know what
                        fear was and when the town became too
                        hot to hold him calmly walked out
                        down the length of the main street
                        through a continuous cross-lire from both
                        sides. But the friends and relatives of
                        his victims were relentless. Warrants
                        were sworn out and he tied to Durango
                        Col. The leading men of that place
                        feared his presence might discourage im
                        migration and determined to get rid of
                        him. Accordingly one night at 12 Holh-
                        day was awakened by the deep-tolling of
                        the boil that called</text> 
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-02-28/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+cowboy&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.118,-0.26,1.521,0.757,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BAT MASTERSON HERE
                        The Famous Sport on His Wn
                        to Carson
                        AN IMPORTANT FIGURE IN THE
                        A IMORTAT FGUE T
                        COLORADO BRIBERY CASE
                        He Outlines the History of theCon
                        troversy Wants to Read Tom
                        Pattersons Testimony The Cor
                        bettFitzsimmons Fight
                        Bat Masterson the wellknown
                        sporting man who is at present figur
                        ing rather prominently in a bribery
                        case over In Colorado arrived in the
                        city yesterday and will remain for
                        I several days Bat makes no denial
                        of the fact that he came to Salt Lake
                        to escape going on the stand In the
                        bribery Investigation The investigation
                        tion opened Friday evening Bat
                        left a day or so earlier and Is now
                        outside the reach of any legislative
                        subpoena
                        TALKS T THE HERALD
                        To a Herald man Mr Masterson had
                        very little to say I dont want to
                        talk until I can get a copy of Satur I
                        Iso I
                        day mornings Rocky Mountain News
                        so I can see what position Tom Patter
                        son is taking Tom has got all the
                        facts in the case he knows all bout
                        the charges of bribery I made against
                        those fellows and was on the stand
                        before the committee last night Until
                        I see what he said I dont care to
                        talk
                        HISTORY OF THE CASE
                        And then Bat related to the re
                        porter the history of the case
                        Of course you have read the Den I
                        ver papers and know there Is a bill
                        pending in the legislature for the di
                        vision of El Paso county Cripple
                        Creek people whom r represent favor
                        the bill while Colorado Springs peo
                        ple are opposed to It We are entitled
                        to division we pay more taxes than
                        any city in the county and still it f
                        necessary for us to cross a big mount
                        ain to get to the county seat The
                        Colorado Springs people of course are
                        opposed to it because at present it Is
                        a source of great revenue to them
                        They have the money and are using
                        It freely and it was the manner In
                        which they used it that came to my
                        notice ant I preferred charges of
                        briber against a number of legis
                        lators The opposition papers have
                        attempted to make light of it by reference
                        I
                        ence mie my record as a gambler and
                        connection with the sporting fraternity I
                        but Ill have my say when the proper
                        time comes I
                        The charges made by Masterson ere
                        in substance that a deal was made t
                        with a certain senator by which cer
                        tain mine owners were to furnish
                        8000 of which 1000 had already
                        been advanced as a corruption fund
                        with which to defeat the division bill
                        He implicated several senators and as
                        serted he would give their names and
                        prove the charges before an investigation
                        committee
                        gation commitee
                        Masterson has been lobbying In fa
                        vor of division and many of the legis
                        lative members looked upon the j I
                        charges in the light of a scheme to 1
                        disorganize the opposition and bulldoze I
                        the senate Into rushing the measure
                        through i
                        SENATE TAKES IT UP
                        I
                        The senate however took official
                        cognizance of the charges which were
                        printed in the Rocky Mountain News
                        and appointed a committee to Investi
                        gate The committee began Its labors
                        last Friday night but instead or 1a
                        terson appearing l he found it more
                        convenient to make a trip across the
                        state line hence his presence in ZIon I
                        Now Masterson does not care to com
                        mit himself until he has studied Tom I
                        Pattersons testimony after that he
                        may have something to say
                        CORBETT AND FITZSIMMONS I
                        What do you think about the com
                        ing fight between Corbett and Fitz I
                        Simmons the reporter asked chang
                        ing the subject
                        Well now I must really be ex
                        f cused from expressing an opinion re
                        plied the genial Bat Both are
                        very good friends of mine While I
                        I do not
                        may have private opinions I
                        care to ventilate them I will say I
                        however that I have not a cent to bet Ion i
                        on the fight either way I ought to
                        be a goo battle and one worth going
                        far to witness I expect to be there
                        and both will have my good will I I
                        really dont know which of the two 11 i
                        would like to see a winner
                        Bat Masterson Is the same Bat
                        as of old He is genial and obliging
                        of are as
                        His pair steelgray eyes I
                        clear and penetrating as ever He is I
                        fat as he always was and the diamond I i
                        stud in his immaculate shirt front gives
                        out the same brilliant luster</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025294/1903-01-07/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Bat+masterson+cowboy&amp;r=0.094,0.027,0.795,0.396,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BAT MASTERSON SEEMS
                        TO BE IN LUCK AGAIN
                        Bat Masterson, the widely known
                        sport, is the talk of the East at the
                        present time. Bat's latest performance is
                        the winning of $Jo,ooo down in Hot
                        Springs, Arkansas.
                        The sensational part of the performande
                        was the quick way in which the shekels
                        rolled into hlat's pounch. lie sat down
                        to a faro table in a big gambling resort
                        and stayed there just ten hours. He
                        won at the rate of $.t,ooo per hour and
                        whesn he arose was richer to the extent
                        of $tor,0,,,
                        Masterson is a lucky dlog ant always
                        was. lie could wint when nobody else
                        could and he generally picked the winner
                        in the big prizefights.
                        Last spring he was arrested in New
                        York for the alleged swindling of an
                        innocent sport. It was afterwards proved
                        that lint had nothing to dIo with the
                        swindling schemee and he was acquitted.
                        lie is proud of the title "The lonest
                        G amblcr."</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1904-12-11/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+cowboy&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.442,0.377,1.733,0.862,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Earp and Masterson MastersonI
                        I was Wa a8 present too once when a very VCl
                        well weUknown known bad man of the lie southwest S
                        Wyatt Earp no less deliberately and andrecklessly an andrecklessly
                        recklessly gave gR ve so noted a killer as I
                        Bat Masterson 1rRst rs rson n the I
                        edge on him in the i
                        H
                        heat of an extreme soreness against I
                        MajKerson who was then the marshal I
                        of nt Dod e
                        There were a number of the Earp Ear
                        boys bo and one of them Virgil upon I
                        the occlusion OC IQJ1 of axvisit n Jslt to Dodge had I
                        been told by bJ Masterson that that sec
                        tIn tJ nwas was too far north for any IJ of f the
                        Harps and recommended Virgil Earp Ear
                        to get back to the cactus country quick eiuiclijd
                        a jd d sudden Masterson in fact en enced
                        forced t ced this thisrecommendation recommendation at the th point pointof
                        of o f one of his guns and Virgil didnt I
                        see a ee anysanse an n5e ir In arguing against that t at
                        kind k ind of persuasion persuasion So he ducked out I
                        of o f Dodge but when he got down to tc
                        Arizona he told his brother Wyatt the I
                        Bardest h nut of that craggyfamily hon hon1sterson
                        Mfeterson l i terson had hadgiven given him the hotfoot hotfoolof
                        oat of DOdge DOdgeWyatt DOc1toVJatt DOdoWyatt
                        Wyatt rode right rl ht up to Dodge to 5 sec se
                        Masterson about it Wyatt yatt Earp had batever
                        never n ever met Bat Masterson Iaater on but he had hadall hadaU ha
                        all a lt kinds of contempt and scorn for the themarshal lhemnrashal th thnarahal
                        marshal i of Dodge as he had for or any au aiiwn
                        man mHl u wn who did all of his slaughtering In ii
                        tho t h name of the law l w Hje looked upon upolny
                        a any ny vmanwho rfilnn who gatbehind 8lblhfn the screen sr on of ol
                        the t he Jaws authority authorlt to do his
                        gun gu Un fight fighting fightng
                        ing in i as a piece of paste and it was for folze I
                        the t ze purpose of expressing this th opinion opinlorp
                        to t p Bat Masterson that he hurried up to t
                        Dodge DodgeAs DodgeuAs DodgeAs
                        uAs As soon as Wyatt Jatt Earp got into Int
                        Dodge he made hurried inquiry as to towhere toI t twhere
                        where hed be b able to find Masterson Mastersonand Mastersonnd a ter50n ter50nand I
                        and a nd somebody told him that Bat was wasplaying
                        playing p gevenup in the back room of Oi
                        Pack PaekWtngates Wingates hotel bar Earp hiked hikeor I
                        for f or Wingates like
                        a button drummer drummermaking drummermtlt1ng r rmUng
                        making for Or an early morning train
                        Earp clomped into WJngates bar barand ba band
                        and a nd asked the barkeep which of the th thwo EL I
                        two t wo sevenup players at atthe the table was wa
                        Masterson The barkeep nodded in the
                        direction of the marshaj marsha Earp got gotover gotover go
                        over o ver to the sevenup table in acouple acoupleof
                        of o f strides He gave the table a bang
                        with his fist that made the cards dance danceand danceand daneanti
                        and he stuck stuelf his face ace withlu four lou j
                        Inches In i hs of Mastarsons MastarsonsYoure lIastersonsYoure MasterSonsYoure i I
                        Youre a latvmurderin son of ofcoyote a acojote aC03otc
                        coyote Masterson dnst son Earp said to the the1114rshal tb tbmarshal
                        marshal of Dodge and for tjvobits tO bits and andi an ana
                        a poncho Id take them law la guns away awn awn1mm
                        from you ou and run em emown Qowt own your you OUt r
                        throat throatMaaterson throatMasterson throatMaaterson
                        Maaterson who never wasVsv first firstrnter firstrater
                        rater in his business buslnossald and I know lcnowbut knowooked 4
                        Jookd l flustered lIe dldnt know Earp Ear
                        but ne Jte saw that the man who ho was talk talkug
                        Ing l ug tp o him wa waft the thereal real Jhing n fJ1g j
                        4 And Ill give you this much the th
                        best of it Itat at that you u gQuaws dog
                        said Earp lhupThen f fHen
                        Then Hen he deliberately d lb rateh pulled mUcd both b it h t
                        guns from his belt b lt slammeU them down downkilling downon
                        on the table besIde But BatMnstrson last on the 1
                        killing marshal mar l1al of Dodge and stopped a
                        five 1h paces back from the table feeling toeHn toeHnof f elin elinof
                        of his knife knifeFar knifFar
                        Far from wanting wanU g an edge eg ft Earp arp i
                        wa w wa4 deliberate 4ellberntqiy J giving gIvIn lha edge to the themap
                        manwho map who at thattime thatl time hadthe had the record recor l
                        for his quicknessonthe quickness pn O the trigger and
                        th the numberof numbe his killings killingsBut killingsnut t
                        But ut Masterson cavedrit wasnt wasn t the
                        first nor the lAst l Bt tlmetha time tlm th thrIt tl heeaved h hacavedeither caved
                        either Qith r t tOh
                        eitherOh
                        Oh behave he paid weakly weak y and ant1o
                        hoa5sely o l to tho Infuriated iiarp nrp
                        jJEJarp 1 iEayp PWaJk wolkdd ts alkd d bff bfJc Jc to the tJ e tsjblc 1
                        mR jrflttthitff lit11 WlntPIY 8stir t1t r111s liti
                        b bdlt UdlTbltatol c rat on th the P I Ck or
                        ear ta lyijig i31i lFt gfa facem eiU on lh Ja1JI iatil and andi andi anVwalked
                        i walked out not even e n taking the thepr theprcaution pre JprLcautJon precaution
                        caution to walk out backward ba wtrd thus thusshowing th thusshowing s sshowing
                        showing his supreme Contempt 1teI 1pt for the themarshal themarshal the111anJhal
                        marshal at Dodge v Having made the theonly theonly theonly
                        only Masterson wilt he heconslderedhls heconslderedhlsrother considered his
                        brother rother Virgils account a unt squared squaredihe squared</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015761/1905-02-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Bat+Masterson&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.897,-0.322,2.794,1.39,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>BAT" MASTERSON
                        NOW U.S. MARSHAL
                        In the future if you receive a call
                        from the United States marshal you
                        will be wise if you throw up your
                        hands and go along without any
                        fuss. For it is more than likely
                        that the United States will be rep
                        resented by Mr. William Barnaby
                        Masterson, better known as "Bat,"
                        all around "bad man" and "gun
                        fighter," says the New York World.
                        The official announcement has
                        been made that "Bat" is to be ap
                        pointed a deputy for this district,
                        and United States Marshal Henkel
                        expects him to drop in most any
                        day now to take the oath of office.
                        "Bat" owes his appointment direct
                        ly to President Roosevelt, who is
                        his friend and admirer.
                        The president met Masterson
                        when he was ranching in the west,
                        and they have been friends ever
                        since. Masterson was in Washing
                        ton for a week a year ago and had
                        a daily chat with the president
                        about the old days in the west.
                        Masterson is a friend of Captain
                        Seth Bullock of Deadwood, S. D.,
                        another of the president's intimates
                        from the west.
                        "Bat" Masterson is credited with
                        twenty-eight notches on the handle
                        of his "gun," indicating that he has
                        killed that number of men. "Bat"
                        doesen't do much talking ab.mt
                        these episodes in his career, con
                        tenting himself with saying that
                        whatever shooting he has done has
                        been in the strict performance of
                        his duty.
                        "I don't believe in fighting ex
                        cept when I have to," said he.
                        About 1877 he was made marshal
                        of Dodge City, Kan., by the class of
                        gamblers known out there as re
                        spectable, which meant that they
                        would not stand for a crooked game.
                        "Bat's" task was to drive out the
                        crooks, and he proceeded to do it in
                        the most effective manner at the
                        point of his gun. There were run
                        ning street fights, in which pistols
                        rang out like musketry.
                        "Bat" cut the first notch in his
                        gun at a settlement known as Adobe
                        Wall, on the Canadian river, and it
                        was only the fact that his gun spoke
                        an instant before the other fellow's
                        that saved his life.
                        That same night a band of Indi
                        ans led by a renegade negro at
                        tacked Masterson. and his men, and
                        were not put to flight until Master
                        son put a bullet through the negro's
                        heart.
                        Masterson'B greatest record as a
                        man- killer was made when six cow:
                        boys killed his brother in Dodge
                        City. Then they took possession
                        of a dance hall and began to "shoot
                        it up."
                        Into this crowd walked "Bat."
                        "All of you get out of here except
                        the fellows that killed my brother,"
                        he commanded.
                        There was only one movement,
                        and that was for guns, but "Bat"
                        killed the six cowboys.
                        Masterson came to New York in
                        1893 at the request of Thomas
                        Byrnes, then superintendent of po
                        lice. George Gould had been re
                        ceiving a number of letters believed
                        to be from an insane man,, who
                        threatened to kill him on sight.
                        "You had better get a man to
                        look after you who wouldn't be
                        afraid to shoot up Broadway at the
                        noon hour and who would hit what
                        he shot at," was the advice given by
                        Byrnes.
                        "Bat" got the job. The crank
                        was finally arrested outside Helen
                        Gould's house. In 1902 Matterson
                        was arrested with James A. Sulli
                        van, J.-F. Saunders and Leopold
                        Frank, charged with having crooked
                        gambling implements in their pos
                        session. A Chicago man named
                        Snow, stopping at the Waldorf, de
                        clared that the men had swindled
                        him out of $17,000 in Chicago, and
                        followed him to New York, thinking
                        him an easy mark. Masterson
                        proved he had nothing to do with
                        the affair, and was merely fined $10
                        for carrying his famous gun with
                        the twenty-eight notches. He later
                        got his gun back.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1921-10-26/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+cowboy&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.493,-0.208,1.777,0.884,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Bat Masterson, Sport*
                        Writer, Was Credited
                        With Killing 28.
                        NEW YORK. Oct. 15.?Bat Maa
                        terson. credited with bavins klllad
                        twenty-eight men In hla time, died
                        at a desk In the famous "old car
                        barn" offlce of the New Tork Morn
                        ing Telegraph* of which he wae
                        ?porte editor In Ms laat year.,
                        writing a story.
                        William Barclay Mastaraon began
                        hla career aa a gun lighter at the
                        age of 20 in a town called Adobe
                        Walla, somewhere In the Western
                        desert, by killing a man In a poker
                        argument. They took the body out
                        side and the poker game went on.
                        The men rolled up In the blankets
                        when the game had come to a
                        peaceful finish and went to sleep.
                        But fortunately the celling of the
                        house fell on Bat and his bunkjr
                        sometime during the night and they
                        extricated themselves from the
                        wreckage In time to Intercept a
                        band of 200 Indians, led by a negro
                        deserter from the United States
                        cavalry, bent on maasacre.
                        Killed leader.
                        Masterson and his friends began
                        firing and this aroused the other
                        men of the town, preventing a sur
                        prise For fourteen days the In
                        dians. led the negro- ex-cavalry
                        man. continued to attack the town.
                        On the fourteenth day Masterson
                        himself killed the negro and the
                        siege abated.
                        Gen. Nelson A. Miles, famous In
                        dian fighter, beard of Masterson'*
                        conduct In the long battle and made
                        him second In ?mm?nd of a de
                        tachment of eighteen scouts. Later
                        he became sheriff of Dodge City,
                        formerly Fort Dodge. Kans.. and In
                        subsequent years he drifted to
                        Trinidad and Denver aa sheriff. Al
                        though he was required to kill men
                        to maintain the peace during his
                        terms as sheriff. Bat Masterson.
                        during all his fifteeo years on
                        Broadway, was reticent about the
                        shootings, except the Incident In
                        which he hunted down and 'killed
                        four drunken cowboys in Dodge
                        City between sunset and sunrise, to
                        avenge the killing of bis brother
                        by one of them.
                        Bat was one of the last survivors
                        of the old West, but he never capi
                        talised his past?never became a
                        circus plainsman. He had counted
                        Theodore Roosevelt among hla per
                        sonal friends.
                        In his sporting comment here
                        Masterson was always lambasting j
                        prise flghtars. for whom, as a class, j
                        he had no great admiration. He
                        was a familiar figure for years,
                        however, at the ringside In Madison
                        Square Garden.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-11-06/ed-1/?sp=58&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+cowboy&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.93,0.147,2.859,1.422,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
				<!-- User Queries-->
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1905-02-24/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Theodore+Roosevelt+Bat+Masterson&amp;st=image&amp;r=-1.061,-0.286,3.122,1.553,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>President Roosevelt has had the fa
                        mous "Bat" Masterson appointed a dep
                        uty I'. S. Marshal in New York city.
                        '"Bat" is the most noted of the old
                        frontier crowd of man-killers including
                        Wyatt and Virgil Earp, and has a rec
                        ord of having shot twenty-eight men.
                        He first gained a national reputation
                        when he was the boy marshal of Dodge
                        City, Kan. He is also a gambler of
                        wide fame, but a "square" one. "Bat"
                        was received at the White House in
                        February, 1904; he went broke backing
                        Charley Mitchell in the Mitchell-Cor-bett
                        fight; he won $2,000 an hour for
                        five hours playing faro at Hot Springs,
                        Ark., and was arrested in New- York,
                        June 6,. 1902, with three other gamblers
                        and charged with fleecing a westerner
                        out of $17,000 with marked cards. He
                        was acquitted, but fined $10 for carry
                        ing a pistol.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1921-10-26/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=heart+attack+Masterson&amp;r=-0.005,0.039,0.818,0.407,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Gunman of Old
                        Wild West Days
                        Dies at His Desk
                        Bat Masterson, Sport*
                        Writer, Was Credited
                        With Killing 28.
                        NEW YORK. Oct. 15.?Bat Maa
                        terson. credited with bavins klllad
                        twenty-eight men In hla time, died
                        at a desk In the famous "old car
                        barn" offlce of the New Tork Morn
                        ing Telegraph* of which he wae
                        ?porte editor In Ms laat year.,
                        writing a story.
                        William Barclay Mastaraon began
                        hla career aa a gun lighter at the
                        age of 20 in a town called Adobe
                        Walla, somewhere In the Western
                        desert, by killing a man In a poker
                        argument. They took the body out
                        side and the poker game went on.
                        The men rolled up In the blankets
                        when the game had come to a
                        peaceful finish and went to sleep.
                        But fortunately the celling of the
                        house fell on Bat and his bunkjr
                        sometime during the night and they
                        extricated themselves from the
                        wreckage In time to Intercept a
                        band of 200 Indians, led by a negro
                        deserter from the United States
                        cavalry, bent on maasacre.
                        Killed leader.
                        Masterson and his friends began
                        firing and this aroused the other
                        men of the town, preventing a sur
                        prise For fourteen days the In
                        dians. led the negro- ex-cavalry
                        man. continued to attack the town.
                        On the fourteenth day Masterson
                        himself killed the negro and the
                        siege abated.
                        Gen. Nelson A. Miles, famous In
                        dian fighter, beard of Masterson'*
                        conduct In the long battle and made
                        him second In ?mm?nd of a de
                        tachment of eighteen scouts. Later
                        he became sheriff of Dodge City,
                        formerly Fort Dodge. Kans.. and In
                        subsequent years he drifted to
                        Trinidad and Denver aa sheriff. Al
                        though he was required to kill men
                        to maintain the peace during his
                        terms as sheriff. Bat Masterson.
                        during all his fifteeo years on
                        Broadway, was reticent about the
                        shootings, except the Incident In
                        which he hunted down and 'killed
                        four drunken cowboys in Dodge
                        City between sunset and sunrise, to
                        avenge the killing of bis brother
                        by one of them.
                        Bat was one of the last survivors
                        of the old West, but he never capi
                        talised his past?never became a
                        circus plainsman. He had counted
                        Theodore Roosevelt among hla per
                        sonal friends.
                        In his sporting comment here
                        Masterson was always lambasting j
                        prise flghtars. for whom, as a class, j
                        he had no great admiration. He
                        was a familiar figure for years,</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036228/1905-02-22/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Masterson+bad+men&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.351,0.103,0.288,0.286,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>"BAT" MA8TER80N APPOINTED.
                        Famous Peace Officer Now Deputy
                        Marshal in New York.
                        New York, Feb. 21.—United States
                        Marshal Henkel baa announced that
                        William B. Masterson, better known
                        throughout the couhtry as "Bat" Mas
                        terson, is now a deputy United States
                        marshal for this district. It tis un
                        derstood the appointment was made
                        at the solicitation of President Roose
                        velt, who has long been a warm per
                        sonal friend and admirer of the form
                        er Kansas marshal and sheriff.
                        In the far west "Bat" is known as
                        one of the old-time "bad men." He
                        never belonged to that class of bullies
                        who kill for the sake of shedding
                        blood, and only fought when he had
                        to. He is said jo have klned twenty
                        seven white men and a number of
                        Indians and Mexicans.
                        Masterson first came into promi
                        nence as the marshal of Dodge City,
                        Kan. He was put into office by the
                        respectable element—which out there
                        meant the gamblers wuo believed in
                        running honest gqmes. He drove the
                        thieves out of town, but not until more
                        than one pitched batMe had been
                        fought. He kiled his first man in a
                        settlement known' as Adobe Wells, on
                        the Canadian river and he shot just in
                        time to save his own life. That was
                        back in 1874, and that same night he
                        and his companion were attacked by
                        a band of Indlaqs led Dy a renegade
                        negro. The fight lasted for nearly
                        two hours, and the Indians were not
                        finally driven away until their leader
                        tell from a bullet fired from Master
                        son's revolver at close range.
                        Masterson went to Dodge City-in
                        1877, and he waS*imediately made mar
                        shal. At one time the opposition plac
                        ed Masterson in the city jail, and then,
                        after soaking it with kerosene, gave
                        him an hour to promise to leave the
                        place. Masterson says that was the
                        only time in his life when he was
                        frghtened or when he weakened. He
                        waited until the hour was nearly up
                        and then promised to leave. He kept
                        the promise, going to Kansas City,
                        where he gathered his friends about
                        him and with them returned to Dodge
                        City. As he rode in his enemies rode
                        out.
                        Not long after that six cow boys
                        rode into Dodge City from Texas, and.
                        proclaiming themselves to be wild and
                        shaggy wolves, declared that it was
                        their night to howl. Masterson
                        brother attempted to-quiet them, and
                        they shot him through the brain. Then
                        1 they went into a dance hall and pro
                        1
                        I
                        ceeded to make merry. Masterson had
                        heard what had happened. an( i, strap
                        ping on his revolver, he went into
                        the hall and announced that he want
                        ed all of the crowd to leave except the
                        slayers of his brother. The shunting
                        began forthwith, and it did not end
                        until the six cowboys were dead. At
                        that time he was believed to be the
                        best shot with a revolver in America.
                        After Masterson left Ford county
                        Kan., hè went to Denver, where he
                        was appointed a United States dep
                        uty marshal, and In the fall of 1893
                        he came to New York, where for
                        months he acted as a body guard for
                        George Gould, whose life had been
                        threatened by an anonymous writer
                        He has been employed at the race
                        track by a number of bookmakers,
                        who thought It good insurance to have
                        Masterson handy In case someone at
                        tempted to get their bank rolls.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/collections/chronicling-america/?ops=AND&amp;qs=journalist+Bat+Masterson&amp;searchType=advanced</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1905-02-24/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Bat+Masterson+Wyatt+Earp&amp;r=0.075,0.351,0.562,0.279,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>President Roosevelt has had the fa
                        mous "Bat" Masterson appointed a dep
                        uty I'. S. Marshal in New York city.
                        '"Bat" is the most noted of the old
                        frontier crowd of man-killers including
                        Wyatt and Virgil Earp, and has a rec
                        ord of having shot twenty-eight men.
                        He first gained a national reputation
                        when he was the boy marshal of Dodge
                        City, Kan. He is also a gambler of
                        wide fame, but a "square" one. "Bat"
                        was received at the White House in
                        February, 1904; he went broke backing
                        Charley Mitchell in the Mitchell-Cor-bett
                        fight; he won $2,000 an hour for
                        five hours playing faro at Hot Springs,
                        Ark., and was arrested in New- York,
                        June 6,. 1902, with three other gamblers
                        and charged with fleecing a westerner
                        out of $17,000 with marked cards. He
                        was acquitted, but fined $10 for carry
                        ing a pistol.</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	<topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-electric-cars</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064454/1891-10-31/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Carriage+carriage+electric+Electric&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.333,0.69,1.964,0.977,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Building an Electric C'arriage.
                        A novelty among vehlieles in this
                        country, an electric carriage, is now
                        beinig coni)strucllted at the faet'rv of
                        IM. W. Qutinlan, in Brookline. Mass.,
                        front plans drawn front a photograph
                        of a similar carriage in nresent use in
                        London. The battery contains thirty.
                        two cells,aoid is jplaced in the rear end
                        of the body of 4ileo carriage. The
                        motor, which is of foreign manutfao
                        ture, rests between the hitd springs,
                        where it is attached to the body by
                        two hinge clasps in such a manner as
                        to allow it to swing when the motion
                        of the carriage is irregular, although
                        this swing is regulated by a connect
                        ing rod. The driving shfts of the
                        miotor extetd on eithcir side ibeyond
                        lthe sprinigs, and are fitted wilh cog
                        wheel attachittents which coninect by
                        atln endless chlati with larger cogwheels
                        on the inner side of the rear wheels.
                        Thie steering apparatus is on the left
                        side of the carriage platform. In case
                        of accildent to the amotor, shafts can be
                        litted to the c:u'riage, and horses at.
                        tached. When comnileted, tie whole
                        carriage will weighl about 2500
                        pouttds. All tlhe electrical work is
                        tlone by the loltiier-Cabot Cotl,:ny*.
                        -[New York ''Tribune.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024546/1891-12-09/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=carriage+electrical&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.328,0.21,1.168,0.581,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>PAVEMENTS MADE FROM OAK AND ICON
                        An electrical carriage has been shipped to
                        Chicago from Des Moines, Iowa. It may
                        arrive to-day, and as soon as its storage bat
                        teries can be charged it will be sent spin
                        ning alont; the boulevards. It was built for
                        ordinary usage and it is said to have carried
                        12 people at a speed ot 14 miles an hour
                        and can run continuously for 13 hours be
                        fore the energy is exhausted. The motor
                        ued is rated at four-horse power, and
                        has an armature of the Siemens type with
                        special-wound coils. The prominent feature
                        of the carriage is the storage cells, 24 in
                        number placed in three sets of eight each.
                        The weight is said to be but 32 pounds per
                        cell audio yield three-horse power hours of
                        energy per cell.
                        The carriage ha a special gearing and a
                        ball and socket motion to the axle, while a
                        peculiar hub device allows for any obstacles
                        encountered. The motor is carried by a
                        framework underneath the body of the car
                        riage and is geared to the rear axle. The
                        steering device is attached to the front uf
                        the axle and is controlled bv a handwheel in
                        the front of the carriage. It is said to be
                        so delicate in action that the course of the
                        chicle can be altered bv a slight touch.
                        The switch for throwing the motor in and
                        out ot circuit is moved by the foot of the
                        one in charge. This carriage is said to have
                        ascended grades or 17 per cent without
                        severe strains.
                        A Frenchman has invented an electric
                        gas-leak detector, which is something like
                        an aneroid barometer. It consists of a
                        acuum chamber working a contact piece.
                        The diaphragm is dilated by the pressure
                        of the gas, and by means ot a lever arm
                        placed on the diaphragm an electric contact
                        is made, ringing a bell. The instrument is
                        said to be ery delicate, and its utility will
                        be appreciated in large factories where
                        much gas is used.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1892-08-11/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=electricity+Electricity+Morrison+wagon+Wagons+William&amp;r=0.103,0.996,0.553,0.275,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Wagons May Now Be Run by
                        Electricity.
                        Chicago, Aug, 10.— A novelty in the
                        way of a wagon propelled by electricity
                        was seen on the streets of Chicago yes
                        terday. Some time ago President J. B.
                        McDonald, of the American Battery
                        company, purchased several patents
                        from William Morrison, of Dcs Moines.
                        Among other things was a park wagon
                        equipped with a small three-horse-power
                        motor and twenty-four-cell storage bat
                        tery. Yesterday Mr. McDonald fitted
                        the wagon with new batteries and gave
                        it a trial. With five persons in the
                        wagon it left the barn on Monroe
                        street and traveled to the company's
                        office. The run was made in twenty
                        two minutes, which was considered a
                        satisfactory, considering that the wagon
                        was delayed at a bridge and that fre
                        quent stops were, made on account of
                        the crowds in the streets down town.
                        It is calculated that the wagon can
                        make ten miles an hour easily with the
                        present motor and can climb any bill in
                        the city.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1895-12-03/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=carriage+carriages+Company+company+electric+Electric+electricity+Morris+Salom+Wagon+wagon+wagons&amp;st=image&amp;r=0.12,0.277,0.882,0.439,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>"On the evening before the race eleven
                        competitors declared they would start, but
                        the next morning when the motocycles were
                        :ent on their tifty-four-mile run only six
                        wagons hael appeared at Jackson Park and
                        midway plaisance. These were:
                        "5 Duryea Motor Wagon Company,
                        Springfield, Mass., gasoline.
                        "7?De la Vergne Refrigerating Machine
                        Company, Now York, gasoline.
                        "18?Morris Salom, Philadelphia, elec
                        tric.
                        "18?M. Mueller Co., Decatur, ill., gas
                        oline.
                        "?!?R. H. Macy Company, New York,
                        gasoline.
                        "25?Sturges Electric Motocycle, Chicago,
                        electric.
                        "The owners of the electric wagons did
                        not start out with the idea of winning the
                        race. They were unable to arrange for sup
                        ply stations at different places along the
                        route and consequently could not get enough
                        power to run over the route to Evanston and
                        back. Dut they Intended to show that their
                        electric wagons could travel under all con
                        ditions us well as the gasoline motor ma
                        chines, anel they considered their test proved
                        the practicability of electricity for horseless
                        carriages.
                        "The three wagons which distanced all
                        competitors?the Duryea, Mueller anel the
                        Macy?were all ?f German make, with some
                        American improvements. They carried Im
                        proved Btnz motors, the Mueller wagon be
                        ing Imported direct from Mannheim, Ger
                        many. The De la \rergne wagon, which won
                        the first prl7o In the Paris-Bordeaux race
                        lest June, also carried a* Benz motor, but
                        this falleil to drive the vehicle through the
                        deep snow at a satisfactory rate, and it
                        droppetl out of tho rage early."</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-02-02/ed-1/?sp=25&amp;q=Carriage+carriage+carriages+electric+Electric+electrical+electricity+Horseless+horseless+Morris+Salom+wagon&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.221,0.789,0.377,0.375,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>The "PJlectrqbat 1 is the original name
                        given by Morris Salom of Philadelphia j
                        to the first electric wagon constructed in i
                        that city. It was ihe joint work of a me-
                        chanical engineer and an electrician. The
                        i wagon was run hundreds of miles over
                        the streets of Philadelphia without seri- j
                        i ous mishap. Its tot.il weight, including
                        I the battery, is 4250 pounds, and the max;- j
                        mum mileage on one charge of electricity
                        la from h'fty to one hundred, according to j
                        speed and grades, the maximum speed at- j
                        tamable being- fifteen miles an hour.
                        Charles A. Duryea of Peoria, 111., ha 3
                        successfully applied the gasoline motor to
                        horselessvehici.es. The Duryea motor re
                        sembles an ordinary, heavily buih buggy,
                        weighs 700 pounds,* and has ball-bearings
                        An Electrobat.
                        [Reproduced from the Cosmopolitan.]
                        and rubber-tired wheels. It has an inge
                        nious mechanism for steering and changing
                        the speed without a moment's loss at time.
                        The cost of running this carriage is one
                        fourth of- a cent a mile, and a supply of
                        gasoline can be carried sufficient to nm
                        the machine 150 miles. Upon goo* roads
                        a SDeed of twenty miles is claimed.
                        There are numerous rivals for popularity
                        in the motocycle world. The Mueller
                        patent, for instance, recently won a prize
                        in a contest for economy of operation,
                        coming in a close seconci'to the Dnryea
                        machine. In order to stimulate invention
                        and do what they can to hasten the com
                        ing of the age of the marvelous carriage
                        the publishers of the Cosmopolitan, from
                        which publication the illustrations of
                        motocycles on this page are taken, offer
                        premiums amounting to $3000. These
                        premiums are to be awarded to motor
                        carriages presenting the greatest number
                        of points of excellence as exhibited in a
                        trial trip to be made from the New York
                        office of the Cosmopolitan on the 30th of
                        May to the Cosmopolitan building at
                        Irvington, and thence back to tbe starting
                        point.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-12-05/ed-1/?sp=25&amp;q=cab+electric+electricity+New+New-York+vehicle+Vehicle+vehicles&amp;r=-0.22,0.93,1.007,0.501,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026853/1897-12-22/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=CABS+cabs+Electric+ELECTRIC+vehicle+vehicles&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.318,-0.082,1.636,1.636,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
                        ELECTRIC CABS IN NEW YORK.
                        Homeless Vehicles Hare Become a Fix*
                        tare In the Biff City.
                        Electric cabs, hansoms and broughams
                        are a sucoesB in New York, so
                        ELECTRIC HANSOM USED IN NEW YOBK.
                        much of a success that the company
                        operating them has just given out an
                        order for 100 new vehicles. Daring
                        Jane, the first moath of their operation,
                        a total number of 632 calls were
                        received, averaging between thirty-Wb
                        and twelve per day, carrying 1680 passengers
                        4603 miles at rates similar to
                        the horse-cab system, and each month
                        sinoe that time has seen a steady increase
                        in the service.
                        The best resalts obtained from these
                        vehicles show that about -1.25 horsepower
                        is supplied for a propulsion of
                        2000 pounds over ordinarily level roads
                        at a speed of ten miles an hour. This
                        consumption of power is a trifle over
                        two and one-third times that of similar
                        work on rails, which indicates that the
                        equipment of the battery is carefully
                        -ii _ f xi J
                        adapted to trie total weigni 01 tue vemcle
                        and just sufficient for practical
                        traveling capacity. The maximum
                        weight of a battery for a hansom weighing
                        3000 pounds is 1200 pounds for a
                        distance of twenty-five miles at the
                        maximum speed of twelve miles or at
                        an average speed of six miles.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1899-02-05/ed-1/?sp=18&amp;q=car+carriage+carriages+cars+electric+electrical+electricity+horseless+vehicle+vehicles&amp;r=-0.083,0.336,0.944,0.469,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-02-02/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=Automobile+automobile+AUTOMOBILE+automobiles+electric+electrical&amp;r=0.575,0.778,0.506,0.251,0</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1913-02-02/ed-1/?sp=80</id>
				<rel>0</rel>
			</result>
			<!-- User searches-->
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030180/1899-03-16/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=electric+cab&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.613,0.375,0.265,0.264,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Each cab is fitted with two two-hore
                        lower electric motors, one of which
                        ;eared to each driving wheel. The motoi
                        .re attached to the axle adjacent to th
                        vheels. In a rear projecting box the ba
                        eries are placed. These batteries consis
                        if a multitude of lead plates carried I
                        ioxes and Immersed In dilute acid.
                        The vehicle Is steered by the rear wheel
                        5ach steering wheel revolves on a shoi
                        ixle, pivoted close to the hub or an axl<
                        cheese, preserv
                        r improve the fla\
                        cannot cause dysp
                        the best shape
                        They come
                        freshne
                        1 Rp!s5>/??\/^\/c-/]S" SHOULD ij
                        ENGINEERS.!
                        n Intricate and Dangerous
                        ned and Examined
                        ir Streets.
                        4
                        i
                        Trained in Paris.
                        V tree. Above the battery box the driver is
                        seated, and from there the various levers
                        r- are within reach.
                        f Under his seat is the "controller," which
                        r is an electric switch for increasing or
                        X diminishing speed, and a handle from it
                        X comes up beside him on his left.
                        T i In front of him is a long lever connected
                        J with the steering gear, and close to this
                        T lever is a brake treadle. To reverse the
                        vehicle there is another switch to work,
                        r Then, when the driver leaves his cab
                        a. he must never forget to carry with him
                        l. the safety switch, handle, or otherwise his
                        cab may be started oft as a runaway.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1912-07-14/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=electric+autos&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.708,-0.253,1.962,0.976,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>r:. J Jones is the only man who
                        has .1,1 ur.nl to run ;m exclusively
                        ,l...-iri.- auto business in Phoenix. His
                        so.c.ss with the Columbus Electric
                        due as much to his marvel
                        in starting the agency as to the UK-lit
                        ,f his cars.
                        He has li.cn here ahoiit eight
                        ln..l!ths. hut in that short time has
                        many tncuns. m
                        electric vehicles wis acquired in t'ali-!
                        (..iTiia in twenty years ol' close study
                        ami w "i'k.
                        X-xt lair time, says Mr. Jones i lu re
                        will he on exhibition at the auto show i
                        a line of electric motor cars that wilt
                        make I'hoenix sit up and notice the j
                        class. The .lis). lay will consist ex-
                        elcsively ..I' Columbus auto.s, which j
                        have h.-c. .me well known as i superior
                        make of electrically propcll-ed auto- j
                        mol.iie j</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1914-01-11/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=electric+car+battery&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.812,-0.236,2.624,1.305,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>Mr. Ford told a little more yesterday
                        about the new electric car which Is to
                        be put on the uiiirket by his son. Ud
                        sail H. Ford. The new machine, for
                        which Thomas A. Kdlson Is muking tin,
                        storugo natteries and electrical marhin
                        cry, Is to hac an operating radius of
                        ion miles without recharging. Tills Is
                        said to be us good lis present machines
                        citlng sevrrul times J600. the price of
                        the new Ford.
                        The storage battery now being used In
                        the experimental models and these
                        models are making gol, according to
                        Mr. Ford weighs Just 405 pounds, a very
                        large saving In weight over the batteries
                        III present use, and the whole car will
                        weigh between l.luw and l.JOO pounds,
                        which Is less than half tho weight of
                        the usual electric now seen. The new
                        600 electric will be of the ciupo type,
                        us Mr. Ford does not believe that the
                        public cares for an open electric car.
                        Battery Perfected, He Hitys.
                        "The battery Is already perftcted." Mr.
                        Ford said. "There Is nothing mure to be
                        done alsjut the battery nnd. wo are wait
                        ing now only for the completion of the
                        machinery for making the car Itself. The
                        most elllcler.t machinery Is necessary to
                        make n car Mich as the new electric to
                        sell at such u llgurc."
                        The same rcale of wages which the
                        profit sharing scheme of the present Ford
                        company has put Into effect will rule In
                        tho new Ford electric factory, with a $5
                        a day minimum for unskilled male labor
                        Mr. Ford has said, as related a day or
                        so ago In The Scn, that such wages were
                        made possible only by the success of his
                        company and were not possible until such
                        success was attained. He said yesterday
                        that for the llrst year or so It would
                        lint be possible to compute. In advance
                        even tho approximate profits of the new
                        enterprise, but that the employ e of the
                        new factory would receive the benefit of
                        tho wage schedule adopted In tho old Just
                        the Bamc.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015104/1899-08-27/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=electric+wagon&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.589,0.138,1.854,0.922,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>A long table of cost of the mainte
                        nance of the horse is and the
                        stated total for one horse wagon and
                        attendance per day agreed upon as
                        304.83 cents, and that the total weight
                        causing the pull was 2,075 pounds per
                        day.
                        The service conditions of electric
                        wagons in New York was then inquired
                        into upon sixty miles of streets of all
                        grades, the power exerted being care
                        fully ascertained on all kinds of sur
                        faces and grades. The total weight
                        was fourrd to be of wagon, passengers
                        and instruments 4,200 pounds, the ve
                        hicle used being one built for the use
                        of a large dry goods store for delivery
                        purposes.
                        The distance traveled was 0.25 miles,
                        the time actually in motion 52.75 min
                        utes, the average speed 8.44. But as
                        suming all conditions to be equal an
                        effort was made to closely find the fac
                        tor of cost, though the electric wagon
                        was found to be more economic as to
                        time, ease of handling goods and safety
                        in motion..
                        The result was a verdict that for light
                        delivery in service in New York, the
                        electric wagon is the cheaper. Its
                        cost per day was 387.77 cents as against
                        against the 304.83 for the horse wagon.
                        But the electric w r agon cost per pound
                        of delivery was 0.01098 less than where
                        the horse was used. The cost per ton
                        mile was found to be 6.12 less than for
                        the horse wagon. Considering the load
                        only, it was found that the cost of mov
                        ing 500 pounds one mile was 9.232
                        cents, while the cost for the same ser
                        vice, with the horse was at the rate
                        of 0.018404 cents per pound per mile
                        being 0.00194 less on electric than for
                        horse service.
                        The final finding was that for light
                        delivery service, all things being con
                        sidered, and excluding depreciation, the
                        saving by use of the electric wagon
                        was 20 per cent. Including depreciation
                        and assuming it to be 25 per cent, for
                        the electric wagon and only 10 per cent,
                        for the horse wagon, and still there
                        is five per cent to the credit of the au
                        tomobile.</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1956-06-13/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=electric+car&amp;st=image&amp;r=-0.254,0.869,1.734,0.862,0</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>There has been prolonged
                        discussion as to abolishing the
                        electric cars in Washington
                        in favor of all-bus transporta
                        tion. A decision must be made
                        soon, and I hope it will not be
                        a decision to fill the streets of
                        our city with an added fleet
                        of buses. For the electric car,
                        though less mobile than the
                        bus, is much more comfortable
                        to ride in; and no evidence
                        has been produced to prove
                        that it is less swift' than the
                        bus in transit.
                        This agitation for the aboli
                        tion of a great invention—this
                        threatened local victory of
                        gasoline over electricity—re
                        calls vividly to the writer his
                        own lifetime experience with
                        the electric car.
                        I was a boy of 12 when one
                        of the first local installations
                        of the electric car took place
                        in my native town of Newton,
                        Mass., a suburb of Boston.
                        This electric car was a primi
                        tive affair—short, and so
                        bumpy that this would have
                        been unbearable but for the
                        slow speed.
                        I remember the fun we boys
                        had in chasing such a car and
                        jumping on the back platform
                        for a ride when the conductor
                        was up front. The car never
                        went so fast but what, with
                        a backward lean we had ob
                        served in train conductors, we
                        could jump off in safety.
                        Soon the primitive urban
                        electric developed into the
                        swift and smooth-riding inter
                        urban car which in a short
                        time spanned the entire New
                        England countryside. As a
                        youth just out of college, I
                        enjoyed on occasions long
                        distance trips as far north
                        from Boston as Portland, Me.,
                        and as far south as Hartford,
                        Conn.
                        In the summer, riding in
                        these large, easy-rolling open
                        cars was a delightful experi
                        ence. It W’as my endeavor at
                        each terminal and change of
                        cars to secure a front seat on
                        the shady side. Sitting thus in
                        the open air and speeding
                        through towns and through
                        charming countryside scenes,
                        my delight was complete. The
                        modern sports car has nothing
                        more than this to offer, if as
                        much—for it cannot lead one
                        over fields, by verdant brooks,
                        and along the edge of woods
                        and through quaint towns, and
                        all in perfect safety from col
                        lision.
                        This interurban extension of
                        the electric car became the
                        rage, but for all too brief a
                        season. Quietly, and almost un
                        perceptably, a modest little
                        mobile car was threatening the
                        existence of the electric mon
                        ster. Ford, with his good roads
                        program and “every man a
                        car” slogan, was soon to spell
                        the doom of the electric car.
                        Yes, the smaller and more
                        clever vehicle ousted from the
                        planet the electrical dinosaur
                        of locomotion, much to the dis
                        may of stockholders if of no
                        one else. And the iron tracks
                        that crisscrossed the country
                        side had to yield to progress—
                        eventually to disappear com
                        pletely and leave skeletons of
                        bridges and demolished rights
                        of-ways as evidence of a brief
                        but glorious past
                        It seems incredible, looking
                        backward, that single lifetime
                        could span the Initiation, the
                        swift development, and the
                        downfall of such a great inven
                        tion as that of the electric car.’
                        It is certainly a fluent age in
                        which we live. And if we are
                        toi2 much disturbed by dif
                        ficulties, national or interna
                        tional. we can find a certain
                        cold comfort—as the Chinese
                        have been wont to do—in the
                        thought: “This too will pass,
                        in time.”</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
</topics>
